<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Obsessed Woodworking</title>
    <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Obsessed Woodworking</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title> Charring Wood for Preservation: The Yakisugi Method</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/is-douglas-fir-rot-resistance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/is-douglas-fir-rot-resistance/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this article, we will explore an ancient method of preserving wood known as charring or the Yakisugi method. There has been a debate about whether timber should be placed in the ground or not, with some advocating for the use of concrete and other alternatives. However, traditional preservatives are no longer as effective as they used to be due to safety regulations. To overcome this issue, charring the wood provides a natural and long-lasting solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Circular Saw Size: Finding the Perfect Fit for Your Needs</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/saw-cutting-capacity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/saw-cutting-capacity/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to choosing a circular saw, size matters. In this article, we will dive deep into the different sizes available and help you determine which one is best suited for your needs. So, whether you&amp;rsquo;re a DIY enthusiast or a professional carpenter, read on to find out more about circular saw sizing.
Understanding Circular Saw Sizes Circular saws come in various sizes, typically measured by the diameter of the blade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Heat-Polymerized Linseed Oil: A Silent Fire Hazard </title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/heat-polymerized-linseed-oil/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/heat-polymerized-linseed-oil/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Many people are unaware of a lurking fire hazard that exists in their homes and workplaces. This threat comes from a seemingly innocent product that is commonly found in every hardware store - linseed oil. Linseed oil is a wood stain and sealant that can lead to devastating fires, even without the presence of a spark. In this article, we will delve into the dangers of linseed oil, explore how it can spontaneously combust, and provide essential safety measures to prevent such incidents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Stain Over MDF: Achieve a Perfect Painted Finish</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-to-stain-over-mdf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-to-stain-over-mdf/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re looking to achieve a flawless painted finish on MDF, you&amp;rsquo;ve come to the right place. In this article, we will guide you through the process of spray painting MDF to make it look glossy and shiny. MDF, or medium-density fiberboard, is a commonly used material in furniture and other household items. While it may have a bad reputation, with the right technique, you can achieve a glass-like finish on your MDF projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Best Firewood for a Cozy Fireplace: A Comprehensive Guide to Choosing the Right Option</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/is-hemlock-good-firewood/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/is-hemlock-good-firewood/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Are you ready to cozy up by the fire on a chilly evening? Choosing the right firewood can make all the difference in creating a warm and inviting atmosphere. In this article, we will explore the various types of firewood and their qualities to help you determine the best option for your fireplace. Whether you prefer hardwood or softwood, we&amp;rsquo;ve got you covered. So, let&amp;rsquo;s dive in!
Key Points Hardwood vs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Increase the Lifespan of a Pine Pergola: Cleaning and Sealing Guide</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-long-will-a-pine-pergola-last/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-long-will-a-pine-pergola-last/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this article, we will discuss the importance of cleaning and sealing a pine pergola to increase its lifespan. A pine pergola can provide a beautiful and functional addition to any outdoor space. However, over time, exposure to the elements can cause the wood to deteriorate and lose its appeal. By following a regular cleaning and sealing routine, you can protect your pine pergola and ensure that it lasts for many years to come.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> **Will Your Clear Varnish Change the Wood&#39;s Color? Understanding Wood Finishes**</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/clear-yellowed-urethane/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/clear-yellowed-urethane/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to woodworking and finishing projects, there&amp;rsquo;s often a debate about whether or not the finish used will alter the wood&amp;rsquo;s natural color. Many individuals believe that certain finishes, such as varnishes, add a yellow or amber hue to the wood, while others prefer to see the wood&amp;rsquo;s natural color unaltered by the finish. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore why yellowing occurs and discuss various types of finishes that may or may not change the wood&amp;rsquo;s appearance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> A Beginner&#39;s Guide to Cedar: One of the Most Versatile Woods Around</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/yellow-cedar-deck-planters/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/yellow-cedar-deck-planters/</guid>
      <description>Cedar is a type of wood that is known for its distinctive smell and versatile properties. In ancient times, cedar was a symbol of power and wealth, and it was used by King David and King Solomon to build palaces and the temple of Jerusalem. In this article, we will explore the different types of cedar, their characteristics, and their various uses.
True Cedar vs. False Cedar: There are four species of true cedar in the world, while most of the cedar trees we know today are false cedars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Finish Acrylic Pour Paintings with Polycrylic: Step by Step Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-you-use-polyurethane-over-acrylic-paint/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-you-use-polyurethane-over-acrylic-paint/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Welcome back to the Meta Pours Fluid Art channel! In this tutorial, we will discuss the process of finishing acrylic pour paintings with polycrylic. Polycrylic is the preferred method for many artists when it comes to varnishing their canvases. It provides a smooth and glossy finish that enhances the artwork&amp;rsquo;s visual appeal. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive into the step-by-step process of using polycrylic to finish your acrylic pour paintings.
Step 1: Gather Your Materials Before we begin, make sure you have all the necessary materials for this tutorial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> **Best Finish for Cornhole Boards in 2023: Protecting Your Investment**</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/best-polyurethane-for-cornhole-boards/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/best-polyurethane-for-cornhole-boards/</guid>
      <description>by Toolz Guru
Introduction If you&amp;rsquo;re a fan of cornhole, then you know the importance of having a high-quality cornhole board. However, sometimes the design of your board may become outdated or worn over time. That&amp;rsquo;s where the best finish for cornhole boards comes in. By refinishing your board with a polyurethane finish, you can not only protect it from the elements but also give it a polished and smooth surface for the bags to slide effortlessly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Downgrade That Blade: Experience the Benefits of a Slightly Smaller Blade</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/slightly-smaller-blade/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/slightly-smaller-blade/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this article, we will explore the advantages of downgrading a table saw blade from a 10-inch blade to a slightly smaller 7 and a quarter-inch framing blade. By making this change, you can achieve smoother cuts, reduce dust, and save money. We will also discuss the recommendations of a master woodworker and provide insight into selecting the appropriate blade size for different woodworking projects. So, let&amp;rsquo;s dive into the details and discover why a slightly smaller blade might be a game-changer for your woodworking endeavors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Remove Broken Dowels: Extracting or Drilling Out | Woodworking Tips</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/removing-glued-wood-dowels/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/removing-glued-wood-dowels/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In the world of furniture repair, encountering a broken dowel is a common issue. But how do you go about removing these pesky pieces without causing further damage? In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll walk you through the steps to effectively remove broken dowels and restore your furniture to its former glory. Whether you choose to extract or drill out the dowels, we&amp;rsquo;ve got you covered with expert tips and techniques.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>  Achieving a Smooth Finish on MDF Cabinets: Best Practices for Painting</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-you-stain-mdf-cabinets/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-you-stain-mdf-cabinets/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this article, we will discuss the best practices for painting MDF (Medium Density Fiberboard) cabinets. MDF is a cost-effective, stable, and easily machinable material, making it ideal for painted cabinets and trim. However, when working with MDF, you may encounter the problem of fuzziness along the edges. This article will guide you through the necessary steps to achieve a smooth finish on your MDF cabinets.
Prepping MDF for Painting Before you begin painting, it is essential to examine the wood or project for any imperfections and fill them in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Brouns &amp; Co Explains the Differences Between Raw and Boiled Linseed Oil for Wood Treatment</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/raw-vs-boiled-linseed-oil/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/raw-vs-boiled-linseed-oil/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this article, we will explore the differences between raw and boiled linseed oil for wood treatment. Linseed oil, derived from flaxseed, is widely known for its health benefits when consumed as a supplement. However, in the realm of wood treatment and preservation, linseed oil takes on a different role. Brouns &amp;amp; Co, an expert in the field, provides valuable insights on the properties and applications of raw and boiled linseed oil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Finish Acrylic Pour Paintings with Polycrylic: Step by Step Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/polyurethane-over-acrylic-paint/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/polyurethane-over-acrylic-paint/</guid>
      <description>Welcome back to Meta Pours Fluid Art! In today&amp;rsquo;s tutorial, we will be discussing how to properly finish and varnish acrylic pour paintings using Minwax Polycrylic. This method is my preferred way of finishing canvases as it gives them a beautiful shimmer and helps protect the artwork. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a beginner or an experienced artist, this step-by-step guide will help you achieve a professional finish on your acrylic pour paintings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Repair and Restore Water Damaged Bubbles in Particle Board Furniture in 8 Simple Steps</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/fake-wood-on-dresser-is-swelling-from-water-damage/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/fake-wood-on-dresser-is-swelling-from-water-damage/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In the world of furniture flipping, finding used furniture in poor condition is a common occurrence. However, with the right knowledge and techniques, even the most damaged pieces can be salvaged and restored to their former glory. In this article, we will discuss how to repair and restore water damaged bubbles in particle board furniture in 8 simple steps. By following these steps, you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to transform a piece of furniture that would have been discarded into one that looks brand new, all while saving yourself a significant amount of money.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Analyzing the Transcript</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/dewalt-circular-saw-20v-problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/dewalt-circular-saw-20v-problems/</guid>
      <description>The transcript is a video review of the DeWALT DCS570 20v MAX XR 7-1/4 Inch Circular Saw. The reviewer discusses the build quality, performance, and features of the circular saw while also tearing it down and examining its components. Some key points mentioned in the video include:
The build quality of the circular saw, specifically the plastic parts and potential weaknesses. The performance of the circular saw with different battery options.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Finishing Your Coasters: How to Seal Wood Coasters to Protect Your Project</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-to-seal-wood-coasters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-to-seal-wood-coasters/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to making wood coasters, the last step is crucial for ensuring their durability and longevity. In this article, we will guide you through the process of sealing your wood coasters using a spray-on polyurethane. By following these steps, you can protect your coasters from any potential damage caused by wet drinks and ensure that your project lasts for years to come.
Step 1: Choose the Right Sealant Before sealing your wood coasters, it&amp;rsquo;s important to select the appropriate sealant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> H1: Cutting Metal With a Scroll Saw: How to Do It Right!</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-you-cut-copper-with-a-scroll-saw/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-you-cut-copper-with-a-scroll-saw/</guid>
      <description>Are you wondering if it&amp;rsquo;s possible to cut metal with a scroll saw? In this article, we will explore the process of cutting metal using a scroll saw and provide you with all the necessary information to do it right! Cutting metal with a scroll saw is not something that many people do often, but it&amp;rsquo;s definitely a capability of this versatile tool. So, let&amp;rsquo;s dive into the details and learn how to cut metal effectively with a scroll saw.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Straighten an Old Barn: Effective Restoration Techniques</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-to-straighten-barn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-to-straighten-barn/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Restoring an old barn can be a challenging but rewarding project. In this article, we will explore the process of straightening an old barn, focusing on one particular method that can help improve the structural integrity and appearance of the roof. By following the steps outlined below, you can bring new life to your barn and ensure its longevity for many more years to come.
Step 1: Assessing the Damage Before starting any restoration work, it&amp;rsquo;s essential to assess the extent of the damage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Polycrylic or Polyurethane: Everything You Need to Know About Wood Finishing</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-polyurethane-be-applied-over-polycrylic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-polyurethane-be-applied-over-polycrylic/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to wood finishing, one of the key decisions you have to make is choosing between polyurethane and polycrylic. While they may sound similar, these two products have notable differences that can affect the outcome of your project. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore the distinctions between polyurethane and polycrylic, and discuss when and how to apply each one.
The Difference Between Polyurethane and Polycrylic The primary difference between polyurethane and polycrylic lies in their composition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> **Alumilite Explains: The Difference Between Epoxy, Polyurethane, and Resin**</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/poly-over-epoxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/poly-over-epoxy/</guid>
      <description>In this article, we are going to dive into the fascinating world of resins and explore the differences between epoxy, polyurethane, and resin. Resin is a broad term that encompasses various synthetic materials, so let&amp;rsquo;s break it down further.
Resin can be classified into two main categories: thermoplastics and thermosetting plastics. Thermoplastics are materials that can be melted or injection molded, such as acrylic, HDPE, and Delrin. However, for the purpose of this discussion, we will focus on the thermosetting plastics, which are liquid initially but become solid and stay solid once cured.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Butcher Block Cutting Board | Purple Heart, Maple, and Walnut: A Stunning Addition to Your Kitchen</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/purple-heart-wood-cutting-board/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/purple-heart-wood-cutting-board/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re looking to add a touch of elegance and functionality to your kitchen, a butcher block cutting board is a must-have item. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss how you can create your own beautiful butcher block cutting board using purple heart wood, maple, and walnut. Follow along as we guide you step by step through the process of creating this stunning piece.
Step 1: Mark and Cut the Lumber To begin, mark your lumber to approximately 25 inches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Apply Water-Based Urethane: A Step-by-Step Guide</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-i-thin-varathane-water-based-poly/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-i-thin-varathane-water-based-poly/</guid>
      <description>Are you wondering how to apply water-based urethane to wood effectively? In this article, we will guide you through the process of applying water-based urethane, step by step. Water-based urethane is a popular choice for wood finishing due to its quick-drying properties and ease of use. Whether you are working with high-quality furniture wood or construction grade lumber, this technique can be applied to any type of wood.
Step 1: Preparing the Urethane Before starting the application process, it is crucial to ensure that the urethane is well-mixed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Use a Miter Saw for DIY Beginners: Tips and Tricks</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-deep-will-a-12in-chop-saw-cut/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-deep-will-a-12in-chop-saw-cut/</guid>
      <description>Are you a DIY beginner looking to tackle some home improvement projects? One essential tool you&amp;rsquo;ll want to have in your arsenal is a chop saw, also known as a miter saw. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll guide you through the process of using a miter saw and share some valuable tips and tricks to help you achieve professional results.
Key Points: The importance of choosing the right chop saw for homeowners The benefits of using a saw stand Understanding the features and functions of a miter saw Proper safety precautions Tips for cutting different materials Making miter cuts for trim carpentry Utilizing positive stops for common angles Handling baseboards and door casings Overcoming obstacles during cuts Unique features for finishing touches Selecting the Right Chop Saw for Homeowners When choosing a miter saw, it is essential to consider your specific needs as a homeowner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Making a Wooden Door that will NEVER Warp</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/make-barn-doors-will-not-warp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/make-barn-doors-will-not-warp/</guid>
      <description>Woodworking is a craft that has been intriguing and captivating people for centuries. From intricate furniture to delicate wooden pieces, the possibilities are endless. In this article, we will delve into the process of making a wooden door that will never warp, a skill that any aspiring woodworker should master.
The Challenge The journey begins with a challenge. The woodworker in the video has taken on a client with a tight deadline of just six days to create and install a barn door.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Single Bevel vs Double Bevel Miter Saws - Which One is Right for You?</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/single-bevel-vs-double-bevel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/single-bevel-vs-double-bevel/</guid>
      <description>In this article, we will be comparing single bevel and double bevel miter saws to help you determine which one is better suited for different situations. Miter saws are essential tools for making precise and accurate cuts on various materials such as wood and metal. However, they come in different types, each with its own advantages and disadvantages. So how do you choose the right one for your needs? Let&amp;rsquo;s find out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> The Truth About Tung Oil Wood Finish: Exploring the Lies and Confusion</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/does-tung-oil-darken-wood/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/does-tung-oil-darken-wood/</guid>
      <description>Tung oil, often lauded as the perfect wood finish, has been surrounded by myths and misconceptions for years. In this article, we will delve into the truth about tung oil, its properties, and its application. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a seasoned woodworker or just starting out, it&amp;rsquo;s crucial to understand what tung oil is, how it works, and how to use it effectively.
What is Tung Oil? Pure tung oil is derived from the nuts of the tung tree, which grows in Asia and South America.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> The Truth About Using Shellac Under Polyurethane – Debunking Myths</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/best-finish-over-shellac/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/best-finish-over-shellac/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In the world of finishing wood projects, there are often conflicting opinions on what techniques work best. One such debate revolves around whether or not it is advisable to use shellac as a sealer under a polyurethane finish. Many experts claim that using shellac under polyurethane can lead to adhesion issues due to the wax content in shellac. However, in this article, we aim to put this myth to rest by conducting an experiment and testing the effectiveness of using shellac under polyurethane.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>  A Step-by-Step Guide on Applying a Boiled Linseed Oil Finish</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/pale-boiled-oil/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/pale-boiled-oil/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this article, we will explore an easy and effective way to finish a piece of wood using boiled linseed oil. This technique allows you to maintain the natural look and feel of the wood while enhancing its figure and color. We will go through a step-by-step process of how to apply boiled linseed oil to achieve a beautiful finish. Additionally, we will discuss safety precautions to ensure a safe and successful application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Applying Teak Oil for a Varnish-Like Finish: A Step-by-Step Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/teak-varnish-vs-oil/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/teak-varnish-vs-oil/</guid>
      <description>Teak oil or varnish? If you&amp;rsquo;re looking to achieve a beautiful finish on your wooden surface, teak oil might be the answer you&amp;rsquo;re looking for. In this three-minute tutorial, we&amp;rsquo;ll guide you through the process of applying teak oil to your wood, resulting in a stunning varnish-like appearance. So, let&amp;rsquo;s get started!
Step 1: Preparing the Surface
Before you begin, it&amp;rsquo;s essential to tape off any edges or areas you don&amp;rsquo;t want the sandpaper to damage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Dewalt Lithium Ion Battery Won&#39;t Charge? Try This Easy Fix</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/20-volt-dewalt-battery-wont-charge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/20-volt-dewalt-battery-wont-charge/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re experiencing trouble charging your Dewalt lithium-ion battery, don&amp;rsquo;t worry - there&amp;rsquo;s a simple fix that can help you get it working again. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to reset your battery so that it can start taking a charge once more. Follow these steps carefully to bring your battery back to life.
What Causes a Lithium Ion Battery to Stop Charging? Sometimes, lithium-ion batteries can become completely depleted, causing them to malfunction and refuse to charge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Fix a 24 Volt Ridgid Battery: Ryobi 24V Tools Running with 18V Ridgid Battery</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-to-fix-24-volt-ridgid-battery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-to-fix-24-volt-ridgid-battery/</guid>
      <description>Are you tired of your 24-volt Ryobi tools running out of battery and leaving your projects unfinished? Well, in this article, we will show you how to fix that problem by using an 18-volt Ridgid battery instead. By making a few modifications, you can power your Ryobi tools with the Ridgid battery and get the job done.
First, let&amp;rsquo;s take a closer look at the similarities between the two batteries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Use Teak Oil for Wood Finishing | Achieve Stunning Results with Furniture Clinic</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-many-coats-of-teak-oil-on-dining-table/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-many-coats-of-teak-oil-on-dining-table/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to finishing wood, using an oil is a great option for providing protection against daily use, weather, and moisture. In addition, oil can enhance the natural beauty of the wood, making it a popular choice among woodworkers. In this article, we will focus on the use of teak oil from Furniture Clinic and explain how to achieve stunning results with this product.
Teak oil, formulated with a traditional recipe of pure tung oil and linseed oil, is a safe and non-toxic option for finishing wood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Lacquer Turning Cloudy After Drying? How to Easily Remove Blushing from Polyurethane</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/remove-blushing-from-polyurethane/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/remove-blushing-from-polyurethane/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In woodworking, it can be frustrating to see white marks or a cloudy appearance on your finished project after applying lacquer. This is especially common when working with wet wood or using stain that hasn&amp;rsquo;t fully dried. But don&amp;rsquo;t worry, there is an easy solution to fix this issue. In this article, we will discuss how to remove blushing from polyurethane using a simple tool and technique. Follow these step-by-step instructions to achieve a perfectly stained finish without any blemishes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> **Polyurethane Over Oiled Wood: A Perfect Finish for Natural Edge Maple Bowl**</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/polyurethane-over-oiled-wood/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/polyurethane-over-oiled-wood/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this article, we will discuss how to apply a polyurethane finish over oiled wood, specifically focusing on a natural edge maple bowl. Polyurethane is an excellent protective coating that provides durability and enhances the natural beauty of wood. We will walk you through the step-by-step process and share some expert tips to achieve the best results. So, let&amp;rsquo;s dive in!
Applying Minwax Wipe-On Polyurethane After turning the natural edge maple bowl, the first step is to apply a coat of mineral oil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> A Comprehensive Guide to Cedar: The Versatile Wood with Amazing Qualities</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-you-use-cedar-for-a-cutting-board/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-you-use-cedar-for-a-cutting-board/</guid>
      <description>Cedar wood holds a special place in human history and has been revered for its unique characteristics and versatility. In this article, we will delve into the world of cedar, exploring its origins, uses, and notable features. We&amp;rsquo;ll also address the difference between true cedar and false cedar, as well as the various applications of cedar in construction, furniture making, and more.
The Distinctive Smell and Symbolism of Cedar Wood has its own distinctive smell, often only noticeable when burned or cut.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Safely Pack a Glass Table Inside a Moving Truck!</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-to-move-a-glass-table-top/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-to-move-a-glass-table-top/</guid>
      <description>Glass furniture pieces, like glass tables, require extra care and attention during a move to ensure they arrive at their destination without any cracks or damages. In this article, we will discuss the step-by-step process of safely packing a glass table inside a moving truck to minimize the risk of breakage. We will also provide expert tips and tricks for maximum protection during transit.
Step 1: Choose the Right Box When packing a glass table, it is crucial to select a heavy-duty box that provides adequate protection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Charring Wood for Preservation: The Yakisugi Method</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/fire-rated-finish-on-wood-when-it-gets-wet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/fire-rated-finish-on-wood-when-it-gets-wet/</guid>
      <description>In recent discussions on the Skill Builder channel, the question of whether timber should be placed in the ground or not has sparked a debate. While most people argue against placing timber directly in the ground and suggest using concrete or alternative solutions, there are some who believe in preserving timber with various methods. However, traditional preservatives are not as effective as they used to be due to safety regulations and reduced effectiveness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Circular Saw: Troubleshooting Guide for Straight Cuts</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/circular-saw-wont-cut-straight/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/circular-saw-wont-cut-straight/</guid>
      <description>Introduction If you&amp;rsquo;ve recently noticed your circular saw smoking, binding up, and struggling to cut straight, you&amp;rsquo;re not alone. Many users encounter this issue, and it can be frustrating to deal with. In this article, we will discuss the common causes of a circular saw not cutting straight and provide step-by-step troubleshooting solutions.
Understanding the Issue One of the main causes of a circular saw not cutting straight is a bent base plate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Achieve a Smooth Finish with Benjamin Moore Command Paint Using a FUJI HVLP Sprayer</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/spray-latex-with-fuji-hvlp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/spray-latex-with-fuji-hvlp/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this article, we will explore the process of achieving a smooth and professional finish using Benjamin Moore Command paint with a FUJI HVLP spray gun. Benjamin Moore Command paint is known for its fast dry time and hard finish, making it ideal for a variety of projects. By following the steps outlined below, you can achieve a flawless finish that will impress your clients and make your work stand out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Polycrylic or Polyurethane: Choosing the Right Wood Finish</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-i-apply-minwax-polyurethane-over-polycrylic/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-i-apply-minwax-polyurethane-over-polycrylic/</guid>
      <description>Woodworking and DIY projects often require finishes to protect and enhance the natural beauty of the wood. Two popular options for wood finishes are polyurethane and polycrylic. Understanding the differences between these two products is essential for achieving the desired results. In this article, we will explore the characteristics, applications, and benefits of polyurethane and polycrylic, helping you make an informed decision. Whether you are refinishing cabinets, creating tabletops, or embarking on any wood finishing project, this guide will assist you in choosing the right finish for your needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> PVA Glue vs. Titebond Type I Wood Glue: Which is Stronger?</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/pva-glue-vs-elmers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/pva-glue-vs-elmers/</guid>
      <description>Woodworking Explained
When it comes to choosing the right glue for your woodworking projects, it&amp;rsquo;s important to understand the differences between PVA glue and Titebond Type I wood glue. In this article, we will compare the two and determine which one is stronger.
PVA glue, also known as school glue, is made from polyvinyl acetate, a vinyl polymer that exhibits excellent adhesion properties for coarse materials like paper and wood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Tinting Tung or Tru Oil with Wood Dyes: A Step-by-Step Demonstration</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-you-use-water-dye-wood-on-danish-oil/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-you-use-water-dye-wood-on-danish-oil/</guid>
      <description>In this article, we will be discussing how to tint tung or tru oil with wood dyes. Tinting is a great way to add color and depth to your woodworking projects, and with the Keda Liquid Dye, you can easily mix it with tung or tru oil to achieve the desired result. This demonstration will show you how to mix the dye with the oil and provide some tips on how to apply it for a beautiful finish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> **The ONE Difference Between MAHOGANY Lumbers: A Comprehensive Guide for Woodworkers**</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/working-with-mahogany-wood/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/working-with-mahogany-wood/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In the world of woodworking, the term &amp;ldquo;mahogany&amp;rdquo; is often associated with elegance, beautiful grain, and a subtle bronze reddish color. However, the problem arises when various woods are labeled as mahogany, creating confusion among woodworkers. In this article, we will explore the key differences between different types of mahogany woods and how understanding these differences can enhance your woodworking projects. We will focus on four commonly encountered mahogany lumbers: genuine mahogany, African mahogany, sapele, and Santos mahogany.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Fixing Polyurethane Bubbles, Puddles, Runs, and Brush Marks: A Comprehensive Guide to Achieving a Flawless Finish</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-you-use-heat-on-polyurethane/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-you-use-heat-on-polyurethane/</guid>
      <description>Polyurethane is a popular choice for finishing woodworking projects due to its durability and beautiful finish. However, it is not uncommon to encounter issues such as bubbles, puddles, runs, and brush marks when applying polyurethane. In this article, we will guide you through the process of fixing these flaws, ensuring a flawless finish that meets your expectations.
As an experienced woodworker with over 30 years of experience, Paul understands the frustrations that can arise when flaws appear in a polyurethane finish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Fix Stripped Screw Holes and Prevent Future Issues</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-you-drill-into-wood-glue/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-you-drill-into-wood-glue/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever experienced the frustration of a stripped screw hole, you know how it can derail your DIY projects. But fear not! There are simple and effective solutions to this common problem. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore different techniques to fix stripped screw holes using easy-to-find materials.
Solution 1: Replace the Screw with a Slightly Longer One Sometimes, all you need is a little extra length to get a secure hold.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Table Saw Comparison: Contractor Saw vs. Cabinet Saw</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/sawstop-contractor-saw-vs-professional/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/sawstop-contractor-saw-vs-professional/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to choosing a table saw for your woodworking needs, there are two main options to consider: the contractor saw and the cabinet saw. In this article, we will explore the differences between these two types of saws and help you determine which one is the right choice for you.
Table saws are incredibly versatile tools that can handle a wide range of tasks. From rip cuts to miters, and even complex joinery and molding work, table saws have become an essential tool for woodworkers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> The Painter, Inc: How to Properly Apply Crawford&#39;s Painter&#39;s Putty for a Flawless Paint Finish</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-you-sand-crawfords-painters-putty/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-you-sand-crawfords-painters-putty/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In the world of painting and woodworking, achieving a flawless finish is key. One essential step in the process is properly applying putty to fill in small holes and imperfections. In this article, we will guide you through the process of using Crawford&amp;rsquo;s Painter&amp;rsquo;s Putty, a specialized product designed for woodwork and interior areas that are going to be painted. We&amp;rsquo;ll cover everything from the tools you&amp;rsquo;ll need, how to prepare the putty, to the step-by-step application process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Varnish and Epoxy: A Professional Wood Finish for Teak Part 1</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/spar-urethane-over-epoxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/spar-urethane-over-epoxy/</guid>
      <description>Varnishing wood is a traditional technique that, when done properly, results in a stunningly beautiful finish. However, the process can be time-consuming and labor-intensive, which is why many people choose to hire professionals for the job. In this episode, we will explore a new approach to varnishing that combines the use of epoxy and traditional varnish to achieve a professional wood finish for teak.
The Advantages of Using Epoxy and Varnish Using epoxy as a build-up coat before applying varnish has several advantages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Watch This Before Buying Paste Wax For Your Woodworking Shop: Achieve a Unique Finish with Johnson&#39;s Paste Wax</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-johnsons-paste-wax-warning-label/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-johnsons-paste-wax-warning-label/</guid>
      <description>Introduction As a woodworker, finding the right finish for your projects is crucial. In this article, we will discuss the use of paste wax as a finish for wood and explore its versatile applications in the woodworking shop. Whether you are looking for a clear coating on wood, a smooth glide on tabletops or tools, or a unique antique look, paste wax can be a valuable addition to your inventory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> What Kind of Finish Should You Use for Wood Projects? | Wood Finishing Basics</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/polyurethane-coat-too-yellow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/polyurethane-coat-too-yellow/</guid>
      <description>Are you unsure about what type of finish to use for your wood projects? Applying a wood finish doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be complicated. In this article, we will discuss the basics of wood finishing to help you make the right choice for your projects.
Key Points:
Some projects may not require any finish at all, such as shop cabinets or work benches. A wood finish helps protect wood from scratches, moisture damage, spills, stains, and UV damage from sunlight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How Long Does It Take for Beeswax to Dry: Unveiling the Mystery of Candle Curing 🕯️</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-long-does-it-take-for-beeswax-to-dry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-long-does-it-take-for-beeswax-to-dry/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to making candles, there&amp;rsquo;s a question that has puzzled many candle enthusiasts and makers alike - do candles need to cure? In this article, we will explore the answer to this age-old question and shed light on the fascinating process of candle curing. So, if you&amp;rsquo;ve ever wondered how long it takes for beeswax to dry or any other type of wax, keep reading to find out!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Mixing Stain &amp; Polyurethane: What Happened?</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-you-stain-over-polyurethane/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-you-stain-over-polyurethane/</guid>
      <description>Note: This article is a transcription of a YouTube video by Alley Picked. The content has been rewritten and structured to provide a detailed understanding of the topic. Please refer to the video for a visual demonstration.
Introduction Have you ever wondered what would happen if you mixed oil-based stain with oil-based polyurethane and then applied it to wood? Would you get the same results as applying the stain first and then the poly?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>  Choosing the Right Circular Saw Size: A Comprehensive Guide</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-deep-does-6.5-inch-saw-cut/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-deep-does-6.5-inch-saw-cut/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Are you in the market for a circular saw, but unsure which size is best suited for your needs? While many videos focus on the performance and quality of various circular saws, few explore the topic of size. In this article, we will delve into the different sizes of circular saws and help you determine which one is ideal for your projects. We will discuss the maximum cutting depth at different angles and provide detailed measurements for each size.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Best Clear Coat Over Latex Paint Of 2022: Protecting and Enhancing Your Surfaces</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/latex-paint-over-polycrylic-finish/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/latex-paint-over-polycrylic-finish/</guid>
      <description>Introduction When it comes to painting surfaces with latex paint, adding a clear coat can provide numerous benefits. A clear coat not only protects surfaces from damage caused by water, alcohol, shipping, or abrasion, but it also enhances the durability of the painted surface. In this article, we will explore the five best clear coats available in the market for latex paint in 2022. Along with that, we will discuss the factors you should consider before buying a clear coat and provide step-by-step instructions on how to apply the clear coat over latex paint.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Hemlock &amp; Oak Planner - A Comprehensive Review and Flip Through for 2023</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-hard-is-hemlock-compared-to-oak/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-hard-is-hemlock-compared-to-oak/</guid>
      <description>In this article, we will be taking a detailed look at the Hemlock and Oak undated weekly planner, which is Jennifer&amp;rsquo;s catch-all planner for July through December 2023. This planner is known for its beautiful design and functional layout, making it an excellent choice for those looking to switch things up.
Introduction Jennifer begins by expressing her excitement over her new Hemlock and Oak planner. She explains that she had been using a B5 Archer and Olive notebook for the first half of 2023 but felt the need for something new and different as June came to an end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Makita vs. Festool: A Comprehensive Comparison &amp; Review of Track Saws</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/festool-vs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/festool-vs/</guid>
      <description>Track saws have become a popular tool in woodworking shops due to their ability to deliver precise and accurate cuts. In this article, we will be comparing two top brands in the market, the Makita and Festool track saws. We will delve into the key features, similarities, and differences between these two models to help you make an informed decision. So, let&amp;rsquo;s dive in!
Introduction to Track Saws Before we jump into the comparison, let&amp;rsquo;s briefly discuss what track saws are and what they are used for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Mixing Stain &amp; Polyurethane: What Happened?</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-you-mix-polyurethane-with-stains/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-you-mix-polyurethane-with-stains/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to finishing wood, there are various techniques and products available. One question that often arises is whether it is possible to mix oil-based stain with oil-based polyurethane and achieve the same results as applying them separately. In this article, we will explore this topic and provide insights into what happens when you mix stain and polyurethane. We will also discuss a real-world application of this technique and offer our opinion on its efficacy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Finishing Your Coasters - How to Waterproof Wood Coasters</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-to-waterproof-wood-coasters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-to-waterproof-wood-coasters/</guid>
      <description>Wood coasters are a beautiful addition to any home, but they can be vulnerable to damage from wet drinks. To protect and preserve the wood, it&amp;rsquo;s important to seal them properly. In this article, we will guide you through the process of sealing your wood coasters using a clear polyurethane spray.
Step-by-Step Guide to Sealing Wood Coasters Step 1: Prepare the Work Area Before you begin the sealing process, ensure that you are working in a well-ventilated area with good weather conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How Strong is Pine Wood Compared to Other Woods? - Waterjet Test</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/pine-hardness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/pine-hardness/</guid>
      <description>The Waterjet Channel recently conducted a series of tests to determine the strength and hardness of different types of wood. They compared balsa, known as the world&amp;rsquo;s softest wood, to yarn wood, which is known to be one of the hardest woods in the world. In this article, we will take a closer look at the experiment and discuss the findings.
The first test conducted was the Janka hardness test, which measures the force required to push a steel ball into the wood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Choose the Right Wood Finish For Your Project: A Comprehensive Guide</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/teak-oil-on-soft-wood/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/teak-oil-on-soft-wood/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to woodworking projects, choosing the right wood finish can be overwhelming. With so many options available, it can be difficult to determine which finish is best for your specific project. In this article, we will discuss the differences between various wood finishes and provide a step-by-step guide on how to choose the right one for your needs.
Wood finishes serve multiple purposes, including protecting the wood from moisture, UV rays, and wear and tear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Makita Track Saw vs Kreg Accu-Cut: Which One is Right for You?</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/kreg-track-saw-vs-makita/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/kreg-track-saw-vs-makita/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re a woodworking enthusiast or professional, you know the importance of having the right tools. One tool that can greatly enhance your cutting capabilities is a track saw. In this article, we will compare two popular track saws - the Makita Track Saw and the Kreg Accu-Cut - to help you decide which one is the better fit for your needs.
Why Choose a Track Saw? A track saw is a versatile cutting tool that allows for precise and accurate cuts on various materials, including plywood, melamine, and solid wood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Refinishing - Eliminating White Blush Made Easy: A Step-by-Step Guide</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-to-remove-wood-blushing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-to-remove-wood-blushing/</guid>
      <description>Are you tired of seeing unsightly white blushes on your furniture&amp;rsquo;s finish? Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, we&amp;rsquo;ve got you covered. In this article, we will guide you through the process of removing wood blushing with ease. Using a powerful solution and a few simple steps, you can resolve this issue without the need to strip and refinish the entire piece. Get ready to learn how to transform your furniture and maintain its pristine appearance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Should you use Varathane Spar Urethane? Outdoor Finish Review</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-long-does-polyurethane-last-outdoors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-long-does-polyurethane-last-outdoors/</guid>
      <description>By TJE Builds
Introduction
When it comes to outdoor finishes for furniture, it is important to choose a product that can withstand the elements and provide long-lasting protection. In this article, we will be reviewing the performance of Varathane Spar Urethane as an outdoor finish. The verdict? Not so great. We will delve into the details of the product&amp;rsquo;s shortcomings, its inability to withstand sunlight, its lack of wood penetration, and the hassle it creates when it comes to restoration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Can You Stain Painted Furniture? Transforming an MDF Dresser with Sanding and Stain</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/staining-mdf-dresser/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/staining-mdf-dresser/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wondered if it&amp;rsquo;s possible to stain painted furniture? In this article, we will explore the process of transforming an MDF dresser with sanding and stain. We will discuss the importance of preparation, the challenges of working with MDF, and the steps involved in achieving a beautiful finish. So, let&amp;rsquo;s dive in!
Preparation Is Key Before beginning any refinishing project, it&amp;rsquo;s important to prepare the piece properly. Start by removing any hardware from the dresser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Distinguish Between Pine, Spruce, Fir, and Larch | The Ultimate Guide to Identifying Conifer Trees</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/difference-between-pine-and-fir-wood/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/difference-between-pine-and-fir-wood/</guid>
      <description>Coniferous trees, commonly known as evergreen or pine trees, are a familiar sight during our childhood. However, many people struggle to distinguish between the various types of conifers in the world, including popular species like fir and spruce. In this article, we will provide you with the easiest and simplest methods to become an expert in identifying conifer trees.
Understanding the Needles The easiest trick to instantly distinguish between pine, spruce, fir, and larch is to observe the needles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Using Varathane Wood Stains and Conditioners to Transform Pine into Walnut</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/turning-pine-into-hardwood/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/turning-pine-into-hardwood/</guid>
      <description>Introduction
In this article, we will explore a woodworking project where we will turn a piece of pine into the look of a walnut. By using Varathane Wood Stains and Conditioners, we can achieve a beautiful walnut finish on our pine project. Follow these step-by-step instructions to create a stunning transformation.
Step 1: Choosing the Right Stain and Conditioner
When working with softwoods like pine, it is important to use a pre-conditioner to seal the wood&amp;rsquo;s pores and prevent a blotchy finish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Achieve a High Durability Finish on a Wooden Threshold with Boiled Linseed Oil and Polyurethane</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/polyurethane-over-boiled-linseed-oil/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/polyurethane-over-boiled-linseed-oil/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this article, we will discuss the process of finishing a wooden threshold using boiled linseed oil and polyurethane. By following these steps, you can achieve a high durability finish that will protect the wood and give it a smooth, glossy appearance. We will also provide some tips and techniques to ensure a successful outcome. So, let&amp;rsquo;s get started!
Step 1: Surface Preparation Before applying any finish, it is important to prepare the surface properly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Maximize the Rip Capacity of Your Table Saw for Woodworking Projects</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/saw-rip-capacity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/saw-rip-capacity/</guid>
      <description>Are you frustrated with the limited rip capacity of your table saw? If you find yourself unable to cut wider pieces of wood or facing challenges with maintaining precision, then this article is for you. In this guide, we will show you a simple yet effective method to upgrade your saw&amp;rsquo;s rip capacity and unlock its full potential. With a few adjustments and tools, you can transform your contractor saw into a versatile woodworking machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> The Importance of Understanding Compatibility between Finishes for Woodworking Projects</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-you-mix-stain-with-boiled-linseed-oil/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-you-mix-stain-with-boiled-linseed-oil/</guid>
      <description>As a woodworker, you may often find yourself faced with the decision of which finishes to use on your projects. While most projects are typically coated with a single type of finish, there are times when you may wish to switch between different finishes for various reasons. However, it is crucial to understand the compatibility between different types of finishes to avoid any potential problems or failures in your woodworking projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> When to Use Pocket Hole Joinery and When Not To</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/pocket-holes-vs-dado/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/pocket-holes-vs-dado/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Woodworkers often utilize pocket hole joinery as a fast and efficient way to create strong joints in their projects. However, it&amp;rsquo;s important to understand when it is appropriate to use pocket screws and when other joinery methods should be considered. This article will discuss the principles of wood expansion and contraction and how it relates to the use of pocket hole joinery. By understanding these concepts, woodworkers can make informed decisions about the best joinery methods for their projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Acrylic Pouring Basics: How to Achieve a Perfect Varnish for Your Paintings</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-you-use-polyurethane-on-painted-canvas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-you-use-polyurethane-on-painted-canvas/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this article, we will discuss the essential techniques and materials needed to achieve a flawless varnish for your acrylic pour paintings. Varnishing your artwork not only enhances its aesthetic appeal but also provides protection against dust, UV rays, and other environmental factors. We will explore the step-by-step process of varnishing, recommended tools and materials, and different varnish options available in the market.
Key Points Introduction to varnishing acrylic pour paintings Importance of varnishing for protection and aesthetic appeal Recommended tools and materials for varnishing Step-by-step process of varnishing Different varnish options and their pros and cons Getting Started with Varnishing When it comes to varnishing acrylic pour paintings, it is crucial to choose the right tools and materials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Finally Finding the Perfect Stain and Boiled Linseed Oil on a 1903a3 Stock</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-you-put-stain-over-linseed-oil/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-you-put-stain-over-linseed-oil/</guid>
      <description>Introduction When working with wood, we&amp;rsquo;re often uncertain of how the final product will look until we apply the finishing touches. In this article, we will explore the process of staining and oiling a 1903a3 stock to enhance its appearance and make it more functional. While stains aren&amp;rsquo;t always preferred, there are times when they can bring out the beauty of the wood. We will discuss the steps involved and the importance of using the right products and techniques.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Apply Water-Based Urethane to Achieve a Smooth Finish</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/thinning-varathane-water-based-polyurethane/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/thinning-varathane-water-based-polyurethane/</guid>
      <description>Introduction
In this article, we will discuss the important technique of applying water-based urethane to wood. Applying urethane may seem simple at first, but it requires careful consideration to achieve a smooth and flawless finish. We will guide you step-by-step on how to apply water-based urethane to your woodworking projects using the appropriate tools and techniques.
Choosing the Right Sheen Level
Before we dive into the application process, it&amp;rsquo;s essential to choose the right sheen level for your project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> STOP Wood Warping BEFORE and AFTER Building! Tips and Tricks for Preventing Wood Warping</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/best-wood-for-cabinet-door-warping/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/best-wood-for-cabinet-door-warping/</guid>
      <description>Introduction One of the most frustrating things in woodworking is bringing home some beautiful lumber only to have it warp or twist after you&amp;rsquo;ve built your project. In this article, we will discuss how to prevent wood from warping and provide you with some valuable tips and tricks. By following these guidelines, you can ensure that your wood remains stable and straight before and after building.
Key Points: Selecting the Right Lumber: Moisture Content, Grain Patterns, and Knots When selecting lumber, pay attention to the moisture content, grain patterns, and knots on the wood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> The Easiest and Simplest Method to Find Your Bandsaw Tire and Blade Size</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/measuring-bandsaw-wheel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/measuring-bandsaw-wheel/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to another episode of the Urban Homesteading Channel! If you&amp;rsquo;re new here, we extend a warm welcome, and if you&amp;rsquo;ve been with us before, welcome back! In our last episode, we tackled the task of creating a portable base for our banjo that had been sitting in storage for quite some time. As we were servicing the banjo, we realized that we needed a new blade and tires. The challenge arose when we couldn&amp;rsquo;t locate the manual, which holds vital information about the blade size.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> DIY Wood Burning Technique - Achieve the Perfect Burnt Wood Finish</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/polyurethane-over-charred-wood/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/polyurethane-over-charred-wood/</guid>
      <description>In this episode of Build Dad Build, we will explore a wood burning technique that creates a stunning burnt wood finish. This technique is often mistaken for the traditional Japanese method called Shou Sugi Ban. We will discuss the tools needed for this project, safety precautions, and additional steps to enhance the final result. Get ready to learn how to achieve that beautiful charred wood look!
Tools Needed Before we dive into the wood burning process, let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at the tools required for this project:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Fixing Intermittent Issues with Dewalt 20V MAX Li Tools</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/dewalt-20v-drill-light-wont-turn-off/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/dewalt-20v-drill-light-wont-turn-off/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Are you experiencing issues with your Dewalt 20V MAX Li tools? Maybe the light won&amp;rsquo;t turn on consistently, and the tool doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to function properly. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, you&amp;rsquo;re not alone in this experience. Many Dewalt users have encountered similar problems with their 20V tools. In this article, we will discuss a simple fix for these intermittent issues.
Understanding the Problem Before we dive into the solution, it&amp;rsquo;s important to understand the root cause of the issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Comparing Natural Boiled Linseed Oils: A Comprehensive Review</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/polymerized-linseed-oil-vs-boiled/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/polymerized-linseed-oil-vs-boiled/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this article, we will be exploring the world of boiled linseed oil, a popular finishing option for woodworking projects. Boiled linseed oil is known for its rich color, luster, and its ability to enhance the natural beauty of wood. While making boiled linseed oil at home can be dangerous and time-consuming, there are several commercial options available on the market that claim to provide the same benefits. In this article, we will be comparing homemade and store-bought boiled linseed oils, as well as exploring other variations such as polymerized linseed oil and linseed oil with additives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Rifle Stock Boiled Linseed Oil: Is More Coats Better? A Comparative Analysis</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-many-coats-of-linseed-oil/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-many-coats-of-linseed-oil/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this article, we will delve into the topic of boiled linseed oil and its application on rifle stocks. Specifically, we will be comparing the number of coats used on two different rifles, a Turkish Mauser with eight coats and an SML A Number One Mark Three with three coats. Many enthusiasts wonder about the ideal number of coats to apply, and we will explore the benefits and considerations of different coat counts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> A Beginner&#39;s Guide to Cedar - Discover the Versatile Nature of this Exceptional Wood</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-long-does-cedar-oil-take-to-dry-on-a-wall/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-long-does-cedar-oil-take-to-dry-on-a-wall/</guid>
      <description>Cedar wood is known for its distinctive smell and versatility. It has been used for centuries and holds symbolical importance in ancient history. In this article, we will delve into the world of cedar, exploring its characteristics, uses, and benefits. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a woodworking enthusiast or simply curious about this remarkable wood, stay tuned to learn more.
True Cedar vs False Cedar: Understanding the Types Contrary to popular belief, there are only four true species of cedar in the world, with three found around the Mediterranean and one in the Himalayas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> A Comprehensive Comparison of Three Rikon Bandsaws for Your Woodworking Workshop</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/rikon-bandsaw-types/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/rikon-bandsaw-types/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Are you in the market for a new bandsaw for your woodworking workshop? Look no further than Rikon bandsaws! In this article, we will provide a detailed comparison of three popular Rikon bandsaw models: the 10-inch, 14-inch, and 18-inch bandsaws. We will discuss their physical characteristics, size differences, and unique features to help you make an informed decision. Whether you have a small workshop or need a powerhouse saw, there is a Rikon bandsaw that&amp;rsquo;s perfect for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Can You Use Shellac Under Polyurethane? Testing for Adhesion Issues</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/oil-based-polyurethane-over-shellac/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/oil-based-polyurethane-over-shellac/</guid>
      <description>In this article, we will address the question of whether or not shellac can be used as a sealer under polyurethane. Many people in the world of finishing have heard that waxed shellac should not be used under polyurethane, but is there any truth to this claim? We will conduct a few tests to determine if there are any adhesion issues when using waxed shellac as a base for polyurethane.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> DIY Outdoor Lumber Rack for Tight Spaces: A Comprehensive Guide</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/store-lumber-outside/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/store-lumber-outside/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this article, we will discuss how to build an outdoor lumber rack for tight spaces. This project is perfect for individuals with limited space in their yard but still want to store full-length lumber pieces and smaller materials in an organized and easily accessible way. Created by One Minute Workbench, this DIY project aims to address the shortcomings of a traditional lumber rack design and provide a long-lasting solution that effectively protects the lumber from the elements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Make a Square Hole in Wood Using a Round Forstner Drill Bit</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-to-chisel-a-square-hole-in-wood/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-to-chisel-a-square-hole-in-wood/</guid>
      <description>Introduction
In woodworking, a square hole is known as a mortise, and it is a crucial component of the mortise and tenon joint, one of the strongest joints in the craft. If you want to build furniture that will last, it is essential to know how to make square holes. In this article, we will explore a simple and effective method for creating square holes using a round forstner drill bit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> The Ultimate Guide to Choosing the Best Track Saw: WEN vs Kreg vs Festool</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/kreg-track-saw-vs-other-track-saws/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/kreg-track-saw-vs-other-track-saws/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re in the market for a track saw, you&amp;rsquo;ve come to the right place. In this article, we will be comparing three popular track saws – the WEN, the Kreg, and the Festool. We will examine their features, performance, and value for money, so you can make an informed decision when purchasing a track saw that fits your needs and budget.
Breakdown of Features Each track saw comes with its own set of features and warranty, so let&amp;rsquo;s break it down:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> What is S-P-F LUMBER? Understanding the Difference Between Spruce Pine Fur and Southern Yellow Pine</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/southern-yellow-pine-vs.-spruce-moisture-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/southern-yellow-pine-vs.-spruce-moisture-control/</guid>
      <description>Introduction: In the construction industry, when purchasing lumber from a store, you may come across the letters &amp;ldquo;SPF&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;SYP&amp;rdquo; stamped on the wood. These markings have significant meanings and can influence the quality and performance of the lumber. This article will dive into the differences between the commonly used spruce pine fur (SPF) lumber and southern yellow pine (SYP) lumber. We will explore the characteristics of each type, their applications, and the factors to consider when choosing the right lumber for your project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Baghouse Filter Maintenance and Troubleshooting: A Comprehensive Guide</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/dust-collector-troubleshooting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/dust-collector-troubleshooting/</guid>
      <description>In today&amp;rsquo;s webinar, presented by Kice Industries, we will be discussing the importance of baghouse filter maintenance and troubleshooting. Baghouse filters are an essential component of dust control systems, and understanding how to properly size, operate, and maintain them is crucial for their optimal performance.
Introduction to Baghouse Filters A baghouse filter is a type of air pollution control device that removes particulate matter from industrial exhaust gas. The air is drawn into the baghouse, where it passes through filtration media, typically fabric filters, that capture and retain the dust particles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> The Secret to Achieving an Amazing Finish with Spray Lacquer in Under 30 Minutes | Wood Finishing Basics</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-many-coats-of-lacquer-on-wood/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-many-coats-of-lacquer-on-wood/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In the world of woodworking, there are certain techniques and materials that can enhance the beauty and durability of your projects. One such material is lacquer, specifically spray lacquer. In this article, we will explore the secret to achieving an incredible finish using spray lacquer in less than 30 minutes. We&amp;rsquo;ll delve into the advantages of lacquer, the application process, and the key steps to obtaining a smooth, professional-looking finish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> The Truth Behind Tung Oil Wood Finish: Debunking Myths and Clearing Confusion</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/is-danish-oil-safe-on-a-countertop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/is-danish-oil-safe-on-a-countertop/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Woodworkers and enthusiasts have long praised Tung oil as the ultimate wood finish. However, amidst all the hype and marketing, there lies a web of lies and confusion. In this article, we will delve into the truth behind Tung oil wood finish, debunking myths and providing clarity on its properties, application, and suitability for different projects.
What is Tung Oil? Tung oil is derived from the nuts of the Tung tree, which is native to Asia and South America.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> What Is S-P-F LUMBER? A Guide to Understanding Lumber Markings and Softwood Varieties</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/southern-yellow-pine-hardness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/southern-yellow-pine-hardness/</guid>
      <description>If you have ever visited a lumber yard, you may have noticed the letters &amp;ldquo;SPF&amp;rdquo; stamped on certain lumber products. While SPF is typically associated with sunscreen, it actually stands for Spruce, Pine, and Fir, which are three types of trees commonly used for lumber. In this article, we will delve into the meaning of these letters and discuss their alternatives.
SPF Lumber: Strength and Lightness
SPF lumber is made from three different types of trees - spruce, pine, and fir.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Apply Danish Oil to Enhance the Beauty of Wood </title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/danish-oil-on-cedar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/danish-oil-on-cedar/</guid>
      <description>Introduction
In this article, we will discuss the process of applying Danish oil to wood. Danish oil is known for its ease of application and ability to enhance the natural beauty of wood. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re refinishing a furniture piece or working on a DIY project, Danish oil can provide a durable and attractive finish. We will also explore the advantages of Danish oil, different application methods, and tips for achieving a smooth and flawless finish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Increase Rip Capacity of Your Table Saw for Improved Woodworking Precision</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/rip-capacity-table-saw/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/rip-capacity-table-saw/</guid>
      <description>Are you frustrated with the limited rip capacity of your table saw? Cutting wider pieces of wood becomes a challenge when your table saw&amp;rsquo;s rip capacity falls short. In this article, we will guide you on how to maximize the rip capacity of your table saw to unlock its full potential and achieve precise woodworking results. By following these steps and utilizing a simple technique, you can overcome the limitations of your table saw and enhance your woodworking capabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Increasing the Crosscut Capacity of a 10 Miter Saw - Laminate Flooring!</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-wide-of-a-board-will-a-10-inch-sliding-miter-saw-cut/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-wide-of-a-board-will-a-10-inch-sliding-miter-saw-cut/</guid>
      <description>Do you have a 10-inch sliding miter saw but need to cut wider boards? In this article, we will guide you through a temporary modification that will allow your saw to cross cut wider boards, specifically for installing laminate flooring. With just a few simple steps, you can increase the crosscut capacity of your 10-inch miter saw and save yourself the need to purchase a new one.
Modifying the Saw Removing the original fence: Start by removing the original fence of your 10-inch sliding miter saw.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Do You Really Need Wood Conditioner When Staining? A Comprehensive Test with Poplar Wood</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/poplar-wood-conditioner-or-primer-before-paint/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/poplar-wood-conditioner-or-primer-before-paint/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Staining wood can be a tricky task, especially when it comes to achieving an even and smooth finish. Many DIY enthusiasts have heard about the recommendation of using a wood conditioner or primer before applying stain. But do you really need it? In this article, we will dive into a comprehensive test using poplar wood to determine whether or not a wood conditioner is necessary. By examining the effects of no conditioner, conditioner, and water on the staining process, we aim to help you make an informed decision for your next project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Prevent Wood Doors from Warping - Exploring the Truth Behind the Myth</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-to-prevent-wood-door-from-warping/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-to-prevent-wood-door-from-warping/</guid>
      <description>Woodworking enthusiasts are often bombarded with various myths and misconceptions, one of which revolves around how to prevent wood panels, such as table tops and cabinet tops, from warping. In this article, we will debunk this myth and provide you with the proper techniques and joinery methods to ensure that your wood doors remain flat over time.
Understanding the Myth Many woodworkers believe that cutting the wood panels into narrower pieces and alternating the end grain when gluing them back together can prevent warping.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Seal Natural Wood Without Darkening or Changing the Color - The Best Products for a Perfect Finish</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/polyurethane-non-yellowing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/polyurethane-non-yellowing/</guid>
      <description>Are you tired of sealing your natural wood only to have it turn yellow, orange, or darker? Look no further! In this article, we will explore the best products on the market to seal natural wood without compromising its beautiful color. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a professional woodworker or a DIY enthusiast, finding the right sealant can make a world of difference. We&amp;rsquo;ve tested various products and identified the top contenders that deliver lasting results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>H1: Spar Urethane vs Polyurethane – Which is the Better Choice for Your Woodworking Project?</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/spar-urethane-over-polyurethane/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/spar-urethane-over-polyurethane/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to woodworking projects, choosing the right protective coat is essential to ensure the longevity and beauty of your creation. Two commonly used products for this purpose are spar urethane and polyurethane. While they may sound similar, there are key differences between the two that can make choosing the right one a bit tricky. In this article, we will delve into the main differences between spar urethane and polyurethane, and when to use each one for the best results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> **Storing Kiln Dried Lumber Outside: Tips and Tricks for Protection and Preservation**</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/storing-kiln-dried-lumber-outside/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/storing-kiln-dried-lumber-outside/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this article, we will discuss the importance of properly storing kiln dried lumber outside. The video transcript we will be referring to is from the HansenBuildings YouTube channel. The video showcases a lumber storage method that ensures the quality and usability of the wood over an extended period. We will highlight the key points and provide detailed explanations to help you understand the process of storing lumber effectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Beeswax Furniture Polish: Achieving the Best Results</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-long-will-beeswax-furniture-polish-last/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-long-will-beeswax-furniture-polish-last/</guid>
      <description>Beeswax furniture polish is the final step in the restoration process of French polishing and finishing furniture. At Gilboys, we have spent years perfecting our craft and have developed our own wax polish to ensure the best results. In this article, we will guide you through the steps of applying beeswax furniture polish at home, providing you with expert tips along the way.
Step 1: Preparation Before applying the wax polish, it is important to prepare your workspace appropriately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Increase the Rip Capacity of Your Table Saw for Woodworking Projects</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/rip-capacity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/rip-capacity/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re an avid woodworker, you know that having a table saw with a limited rip capacity can be quite frustrating. In this article, we will discuss a simple method to increase the rip capacity of your table saw, allowing you to handle wider pieces of wood with ease. By following the steps outlined below, you can unlock the full potential of your contractor saw and expand its capabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Use Teak Oil for Wood Finishing and Maintenance</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/teak-oil-dry-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/teak-oil-dry-time/</guid>
      <description>Teak oil is a popular choice for finishing and maintaining wood due to its ability to provide protection from daily use, weather, and moisture resistance. In addition to its protective qualities, teak oil also enhances the natural beauty of the wood, making it a top choice for both stained and bare wood projects. In this article, we will specifically focus on how to use teak oil effectively to achieve stunning results on various types of wood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Use Teak Oil for Wood Finishing: A Guide by Furniture Clinic</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/teak-oil-drying-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/teak-oil-drying-time/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Wood finishing oils are an excellent choice for protecting and enhancing the beauty of both stained and bare wood. In this comprehensive guide, we will specifically focus on the benefits and application of teak oil, a popular choice for maintaining and preserving wooden furniture, doors, windows, cladding, and fencing. Our teak oil, formulated using a traditional recipe of pure tung oil and linseed oil, not only offers excellent UV protection but also prevents drying, warping, and splitting, maintaining the natural beauty and integrity of the wood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Is Polyurethane Glue Food Safe: Understanding Wood Finishes for Food-Related Projects</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/is-polyurethane-glue-food-safe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/is-polyurethane-glue-food-safe/</guid>
      <description>Wood finishes can be a confusing topic, especially when it comes to their safety for food-related projects. Many people wonder if the finishes used on cutting boards, bowls, and wooden spoons are truly food-safe. In this article, we will debunk common misconceptions and provide a thorough understanding of wood finishes and their safety.
Understanding Food-Safe Labels
One of the main reasons people question the safety of wood finishes is because of the presence or absence of food-safe labels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How Long Can Untreated Wood Survive Outdoors? Testing the Durability of Untreated Wood Planters</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/untreated-wood-vs-sealing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/untreated-wood-vs-sealing/</guid>
      <description>In this video, I am going to address a popular question that many DIY enthusiasts have: how long can untreated wood survive outdoors? A couple of years ago, I built several timber planters out of non-treated timber, despite concerns from viewers that they wouldn&amp;rsquo;t last. Today, I am going to refurbish one of these planters and assess how the non-treated wood has held up after two years of exposure to the elements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> TEAK Wood Farming: A Lucrative Investment for Long-Term Profits</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/treated-teak-trees-in-ghana/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/treated-teak-trees-in-ghana/</guid>
      <description>Investing in teak wood farming can yield significant profits in the long run. In this article, we will explore the process of teak farming in Ghana and discuss why it is a profitable venture. We will also delve into the steps and necessary precautions for successful plantation. Read on to discover how you can earn a lump sum of money through teak wood farming after 10-15 years.
Key Points: Introduction to teak wood farming The types of teak trees and their uses Suitable regions for teak farming in Ghana How to prepare the land for teak plantation Seed versus seedling: Which is better for teak farming?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> What Finish Should You Use? A Guide to Wood Finishing Basics</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-many-coats-of-brushing-lacquer-do-you-need/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-many-coats-of-brushing-lacquer-do-you-need/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to woodworking projects, applying a finish is often essential to protect the wood and enhance its appearance. But with so many options available, choosing the right finish can be overwhelming. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll go over the basics of wood finishing and discuss some of the most common finishes used by hobbyists.
Why Apply a Finish?
Wood finishes serve two main purposes: protection and aesthetics. A good finish helps protect wood from scratches, moisture damage, spills, stains, and UV damage from sunlight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> **How to Seal Cedar Siding with Linseed Oil: Applying and Testing Durability**</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-to-seal-cedar-siding-with-linseed-oil/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-to-seal-cedar-siding-with-linseed-oil/</guid>
      <description>In this article, we will discuss the process of applying linseed oil to wood, specifically cedar siding. Linseed oil is a popular choice for protecting and enhancing the natural beauty of wood, but how durable is it? We will explore the durability of linseed oil and whether it is waterproof.
Before we begin, make sure to check out The Art Company&amp;rsquo;s Youtube channel for more interesting content.
Key Points: Preparing the Board for Linseed Oil Application Applying Linseed Oil with Attention to Knots and Grain Distributing Excess Oil and Buffing the Surface Durability Test and Results Conclusion: Linseed Oil as a Tabletop Finish Preparing the Board for Linseed Oil Application To start the process, ensure that the cedar board is freshly sanded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Cut Picture Frames with a Miter Saw: Step-by-Step Guide</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/metal-picture-frame-miter-saw/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/metal-picture-frame-miter-saw/</guid>
      <description>Picture frames can add a touch of elegance and style to any photograph or artwork. If you want to create your own picture frames, using a miter saw is an efficient and precise method. In this article, we will guide you through the step-by-step process of cutting picture frames using a miter saw. By following these instructions, you will be able to create beautiful frames with ease.
Key Points: Start by cutting the routed profile and rabbet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> The Truth About Rubio Monocoat: Is it Really That Good?</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/rubio-monocoat-getting-wet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/rubio-monocoat-getting-wet/</guid>
      <description>Rubio Monocoat has gained popularity as a hard wax finish for furniture and hand tools. In this article, we will discuss the benefits and drawbacks of using Rubio Monocoat, as well as how to apply it effectively. If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for a protective and visually appealing finish, keep reading to find out if Rubio Monocoat is the right choice for you.
The Appeal of Traditional Finishes Before we dive into the world of Rubio Monocoat, let&amp;rsquo;s explore why traditional finishes like homemade boiled linseed oil and paste wax have captured the hearts of many woodworkers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> A Comprehensive Guide to Cedar: One of the Most Versatile Woods Around!</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/incense-cedar-closets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/incense-cedar-closets/</guid>
      <description>Cedar is a wood that stands out from the rest due to its distinctive smell. Unlike other woods, cedar has a strong and recognizable scent that can be perceived even when it&amp;rsquo;s not being burned or cut. In fact, cedar was so revered in ancient times that it was mentioned in the Bible and associated with power and wealth. Kings David and Solomon used cedar to build palaces and the temple of Jerusalem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Amazing Table Top Finish! - How to Apply Epoxy and Wipe On Poly for a Hand Rubbed Oil Finish</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-you-put-polyurethane-over-epoxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-you-put-polyurethane-over-epoxy/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever wondered how to achieve a beautiful table top finish, look no further! In this article, we will walk you through the process of applying epoxy and wipe on poly to create a stunning hand rubbed oil finish on your wooden tables.
Before we dive into the details, it&amp;rsquo;s important to note that there are different ways of applying an epoxy finish, and the technique you choose should depend on the desired outcome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Finishing Your Coasters: The Best Sealant for Wood Coasters</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/best-sealant-for-wood-coasters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/best-sealant-for-wood-coasters/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve recently crafted some beautiful wooden coasters, you&amp;rsquo;ll want to make sure they are well-protected and can withstand the moisture from wet drinks. In this article, we will guide you on how to seal your coasters effectively using the best sealant for wood coasters.
To ensure your coasters remain durable and resistant to damage, we recommend using a spray-on polyurethane sealant. This type of sealant not only provides a protective barrier but also gives your coasters an attractive clear satin or matte finish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Restore Water Damaged Particle Board Furniture in 8 Simple Steps</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/dresser-top-swells-up-after-water-spill/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/dresser-top-swells-up-after-water-spill/</guid>
      <description>In this article, we will discuss a step-by-step process to repair and restore water damaged particle board furniture. Many times, when you come across used furniture for sale, it may be in poor condition. This tutorial will guide you on how to fix swollen wood and repair particle board, resulting in a piece of furniture that looks brand new.
Before we dive into the steps, it&amp;rsquo;s important to note that you should always wear a mask when working with particle board or MDF furniture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Seal Wood Etching: The Pros and Cons of Danish Oil</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-to-seal-wood-etching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-to-seal-wood-etching/</guid>
      <description>Wood varnishing is a crucial step in preserving and protecting wood burning art. If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for a reliable way to seal your artwork and protect the wood, Danish oil is an excellent option. In this article, we will discuss the pros and cons of Danish oil and provide step-by-step instructions on how to apply it for optimal results.
The Benefits of Danish Oil Danish oil is a blend of varnish and natural oil, making it a versatile product that not only seals the wood but also protects it from stains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Use any Brand Battery in Any Power Tool 18V-20V DEWALT MILWAUKEE MAKITA PORTER CABLE BOSCH Adapters</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/cordless-tool-battery-interchangeable/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/cordless-tool-battery-interchangeable/</guid>
      <description>In today&amp;rsquo;s world of power tools, it can be expensive and inconvenient to invest in multiple battery platforms for different tool brands. However, there is a solution that allows you to use any brand battery in any power tool, regardless of the brand. With the use of simple adapters, you can expand the compatibility of your power tools and save money in the process. In this article, we will explore the benefits of using battery adapters and how they can revolutionize the way you use your power tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> What Makes Oak Cutting Boards Different and Why You Should Opt for White Oak Instead</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/does-oak-make-good-cutting-board/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/does-oak-make-good-cutting-board/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to making a cutting board, one question that frequently arises is whether oak is a suitable wood to use. In this article, we will definitively answer this question and provide valuable insights into why oak may not always be the best choice. Instead, we will explore the benefits of using white oak for cutting boards.
Understanding Why Oak Is Discouraged The primary reason why oak is often discouraged for cutting boards is due to its porous structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Makita Track Saw vs Kreg Accu-Cut: Which One is Right for You?</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/kreg-vs-makita-track-saw/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/kreg-vs-makita-track-saw/</guid>
      <description>Image Source: timesofindia.indiatimes.com
If you&amp;rsquo;re a woodworker looking for a reliable track saw, you&amp;rsquo;ve probably come across the Makita Track Saw and the Kreg Accu-Cut. Both of these tools have gained popularity in the woodworking community, but which one is the right choice for you?
In this article, we will provide a detailed comparison of the Makita Track Saw and the Kreg Accu-Cut, discussing their features, usability, and overall performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> The Simpson Artwork: Creating a 3D Scroll Saw Project from Start to Finish</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/best-wood-for-scroll-saw-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/best-wood-for-scroll-saw-projects/</guid>
      <description>![The Simpson Artwork- Time-lapse (scroll saw project start to finish)](image link)
Are you ready to dive into the world of scroll saw art? In this article, we will take you through the process of creating a stunning 3D Simpson artwork using a scroll saw, from start to finish. Follow along as we explore the tools, techniques, and steps involved in bringing this unique piece to life.
Introduction to Scroll Saw Art Scroll saw art is a form of woodworking that involves using a specialized saw called a scroll saw to create intricate and detailed designs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> A Beginners Guide to Cedar - Discover the Versatility and Benefits of Cedar Wood</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/does-cedar-resist-mold/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/does-cedar-resist-mold/</guid>
      <description>Cedar wood is often recognized for its distinctive smell and unique properties. In ancient times, cedar was considered a symbol of power and wealth, with kings like David and Solomon using cedar to build palaces and temples. Today, cedar continues to be a popular choice for various applications due to its versatility and beneficial characteristics. In this article, we will explore the wonders of cedar wood, discussing its types, features, and practical uses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Dewalt Lithium Ion Battery Won&#39;t Charge? Try This Simple Resetting Technique</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/my-dewalt-battery-will-not-charge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/my-dewalt-battery-will-not-charge/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Are you having trouble with your Dewalt lithium-ion battery not charging? Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, I have a solution for you. In this article, I will show you a simple and effective technique to reset your battery so that it can start taking a charge again. This method is especially useful when your battery has been completely depleted and needs a little boost to kickstart the charging process. Just like how you would have to charge each cell individually in a golf cart, we will give your battery a little jumpstart to get it back in action.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Remove Polycrylic: A Quick and Easy Guide</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/removing-polycrylic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/removing-polycrylic/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Welcome to my shed, where today we will be discussing the process of removing Polycrylic. Polycrylic is a water-based polyurethane used to seal and protect wood surfaces. While it can be a great product for finishing projects, it can also be a challenge to remove if applied incorrectly. In this article, I will walk you through step-by-step on how to properly remove Polycrylic from your wood surfaces.
Step 1: Assess the Situation Before diving into the removal process, it&amp;rsquo;s important to assess the condition of the Polycrylic finish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> What You Need to Know About Staining MDF Wood: Expert Tips and Techniques</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-you-stain-mdf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-you-stain-mdf/</guid>
      <description>If you are working with MDF wood, you may be aware of its lightweight and strong characteristics. However, one issue that can arise with MDF wood is the potential for water damage and bubbling. In this article, we will explore the steps and considerations involved in staining MDF wood to achieve a professional finish and protect your workbench or project.
Key Points: MDF wood is susceptible to water damage and bubbling if exposed to moisture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Wood Burning Tips For Achieving a Shou Sugi Ban Inspired Finish</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/should-i-varnish-after-torching-wood/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/should-i-varnish-after-torching-wood/</guid>
      <description>Wood burning is a popular technique used by DIYers and craftsmen to create unique and beautiful finishes on wood. One technique that has gained popularity is the shou sugi ban inspired burn and brush technique. In this article, we will explore the process of achieving the best finish using this technique, including the question of whether varnishing should be done after torching the wood.
The first step in achieving the desired finish is to gather the necessary tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Advantages of Hemlock Lumber: Pros and Cons Explained</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/hemlock-wood-vs-pine/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/hemlock-wood-vs-pine/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to Hemlock Lumber In this article, we will be discussing the advantages and disadvantages of using hemlock lumber in your building projects. Hemlock lumber is one of the various species of wood that can be found at the Lumber Capital Log Yard sawmill. While the sawmill specializes in hemlock lumber, they also cut other species including hardwoods, pine, and basswood. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re in the middle of a project or trying to make an informed decision on which type of lumber to use, understanding the pros and cons of hemlock can help you make an educated choice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Waterproof Your Wood Boat with Linseed Oil: A Step-by-Step Guide</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/linseed-oil-waterproof-wood-boat/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/linseed-oil-waterproof-wood-boat/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wondered how to protect your wood boat from water damage? Look no further! In this article, we will take you through the process of varnishing wood with linseed oil, a tried and tested method to waterproof your wooden boat. Say goodbye to rotting wood and hello to a sturdy and long-lasting vessel.
Why Linseed Oil?
Before we dive into the step-by-step process, let&amp;rsquo;s first understand why linseed oil is the go-to choice for waterproofing wood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Storing Kiln Dried Construction Lumber Outside: Tips for Protecting Your Investment</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/storing-kiln-dried-construction-lumber-outside/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/storing-kiln-dried-construction-lumber-outside/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this article, we will discuss the importance of properly storing kiln-dried construction lumber outside. Many times, due to various reasons such as weather delays, permitting issues, or waiting for a contractor, project timelines get extended, and it becomes necessary to store the building materials temporarily. One common method to protect these materials is by tarping them up. We will outline the key steps to safeguarding your investment and ensure that your lumber remains in excellent condition for future use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> This SIMPLE Wood Finish Will Save You DAYS of Shop Time!</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-you-dye-stain-over-dewaxed-shellac/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-you-dye-stain-over-dewaxed-shellac/</guid>
      <description>Wood finishing can be a tedious and time-consuming process, often requiring multiple steps and waiting for drying times. However, there is a simple wood finish that can save you days of shop time – shellac. In this article, we will explore why shellac is a great wood finish, how to use it effectively, and when it is the best choice for your projects.
Why Choose Shellac as a Wood Finish?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Does Minwax Wood Hardener Actually Harden Wood?</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-to-make-softwood-harder/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-to-make-softwood-harder/</guid>
      <description>In this article, we will explore the effectiveness of Minwax Wood Hardener in actually hardening wood. We will analyze the results of a test conducted by Shawn in his workshop, where he compared untreated wood with wood treated with Minwax Wood Hardener.
The Composition of Minwax Wood Hardener Before diving into the test results, it is important to understand the composition of Minwax Wood Hardener. Shawn explains that it is a form of plastic dissolved in a solvent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Cut Wide Boards on a Chop Saw: A Step-by-Step Guide</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/10-chop-saw-can-cut-how-wide/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/10-chop-saw-can-cut-how-wide/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this article, we will explore the technique of cutting wide boards on a chop saw. Many people believe that chop saws are limited in their capacity to cut wide boards, but with the right approach, you can achieve a perfect, straight cut on a 12-inch wide board using a standard chop saw. We&amp;rsquo;ll provide step-by-step instructions and useful tips to help you accomplish this task effortlessly.
Step 1: Preparation Before you start cutting, it&amp;rsquo;s essential to gather all the necessary tools and ensure that your chop saw is in proper working condition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> What You Need to Know About Gel Stain: A Versatile Wood Staining Solution</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-you-put-gel-stain-over-polyurethane/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-you-put-gel-stain-over-polyurethane/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this article, we will delve into the world of gel stain, a type of wood stain that offers greater control, versatility, and convenience compared to traditional liquid stains. Unlike its runny counterpart, gel stain is thick and can be used on vertical surfaces without dripping. This article will explore the benefits of gel stain, provide practical tips for using it, and offer guidance on disposing of related materials safely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Dewalt Lithium Ion Batteries Not Charging? Resetting Can Fix It</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/dewalt-batteries-dont-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/dewalt-batteries-dont-work/</guid>
      <description>Lithium ion batteries are known for their efficiency and long lifespan. However, sometimes these batteries can encounter issues, such as not charging properly. In this article, we will discuss a simple and easy fix to reset your Dewalt lithium ion battery and get it charging again.
Understanding the Issue If your lithium ion battery has been completely depleted or left unused for an extended period, it may need to be reset in order to start accepting a charge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Achieve Perfect Results When Staining Wood: A Comprehensive Guide</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-many-coats-of-stain-on-mdf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-many-coats-of-stain-on-mdf/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Wood staining is a popular technique used to enhance the appearance of wood, whether to add color or bring out the natural beauty of the grain. In this article, we will discuss the step-by-step process of staining wood to achieve professional-level results. We will cover the importance of sanding, choosing the right tools, applying a pre-stain conditioner, and selecting the appropriate top coat. By following these guidelines, you can ensure that your stained wood projects look fantastic and stand the test of time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>  5 Affordable and Versatile Wood Options for Your Home Woodworking Projects</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/aspen-wood-vs-alder-wood/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/aspen-wood-vs-alder-wood/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Are you a beginner woodworker who finds the process of choosing wood intimidating? With so many options and unfamiliar terminology, it can be overwhelming. In this article, we will help you make an informed choice and have a better woodworking experience. We will explore five affordable and versatile wood options that are ideal for furniture and decorative home woodworking projects. These woods, namely soft maple, poplar, beech, knotty alder, and white oak, are not only budget-friendly but also easy to work with and visually appealing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> **How to Achieve Smooth and Clean Cuts with a Beadboard Cutter for Table Saw**</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/beadboard-cutter-for-table-saw/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/beadboard-cutter-for-table-saw/</guid>
      <description>Are you tired of rough and uneven cuts on your beadboard or paneling projects? Look no further, because we have a solution for you! In this article, we will discuss the benefits of using an oscillating tool blade specifically designed for beadboards. We will walk you through the step-by-step process of achieving smooth and clean cuts, and show you the advantages of using this tool over a utility knife. So, let&amp;rsquo;s dive in and learn how to make your beadboard projects look flawless!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Apply Linseed Oil on Wood: Exploring Durability and Waterproofing</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/linseed-oil-temperature-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/linseed-oil-temperature-application/</guid>
      <description>In this article, we will delve into the world of linseed oil and discover the best tips and tricks for its application on raw Cedar wood. Additionally, we will test the durability of the oil and determine its waterproofing properties. Whether you are a seasoned woodworker or a DIY enthusiast, this article will provide valuable insights into linseed oil and its use on wooden surfaces. So let&amp;rsquo;s dive in!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Managing Veneer Walnut Trees: Benefits for Whitetails, Timber Improvements, and Habitat</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/walnut-trees-investment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/walnut-trees-investment/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this article, we will explore the benefits of managing veneer walnut trees for whitetail deer, timber improvements, and habitat enhancements. Veneer walnuts are a valuable investment, with the potential to significantly increase in value over time. By properly managing these trees, landowners can create a thriving ecosystem for wildlife while also maximizing their financial returns.
The Value of Veneer Walnut Trees Many people may not consider walnuts as suitable for wildlife, especially deer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> This Simple Wood Finish Will Save You Days of Shop Time: Shellac</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/stain-over-shellac/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/stain-over-shellac/</guid>
      <description>In the world of wood finishing, shellac was once considered the best and most widely used finish. However, modern finish manufacturers have convinced woodworkers that shellac is old-fashioned, and many have turned to polyurethane as their go-to finish. But what they don&amp;rsquo;t realize is that shellac offers numerous benefits that make it a fantastic choice for finishing wood. In this article, we will explore why you should be using shellac, how to use it effectively, and when it is the best option for your woodworking projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Title: The Truth About Using Oak Cutting Boards: Exploring the Pros and Cons</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/oak-as-a-cutting-board/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/oak-as-a-cutting-board/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Choosing the right material for a cutting board can be a daunting task, especially when considering the debate surrounding oak as a suitable option. Many people claim that oak should not be used due to its porous structure, which can lead to bacteria growth and rot. In this article, we will delve into the truth about using oak cutting boards, examining the pros and cons and clarifying which type of oak is suitable for this purpose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Why I Prefer Raw Linseed Oil Over Boiled Linseed Oil for Outdoor Furniture</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/raw-or-boiled-linseed-oil-for-outdoor-furniture/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/raw-or-boiled-linseed-oil-for-outdoor-furniture/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this article, we will discuss the reasons why boiled linseed oil is not recommended for use in outdoor furniture projects. Despite its popularity and effectiveness, boiled linseed oil poses certain risks that may outweigh its benefits. We will explore these risks in detail and provide alternative options for finishing outdoor furniture. Our goal is to ensure that you make informed decisions while working on your projects, prioritizing safety and minimizing potential hazards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How Many Coats of Boiled Linseed Oil Should You Apply for a Perfect Wood Finish?</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-many-coats-of-boiled-linseed-oil/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-many-coats-of-boiled-linseed-oil/</guid>
      <description>Boiled linseed oil is a popular choice for finishing wood because it enhances the natural look and feel of the piece while also bringing out the figure and color of the wood. In this article, we will discuss how to apply boiled linseed oil to achieve a beautiful finish on your wood projects. We will cover the steps, drying times, and optional finishing touches to help you create a professional result.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How Much Load Can a Timber Post Actually Carry?</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-much-weight-can-a-wood-table-hold/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-much-weight-can-a-wood-table-hold/</guid>
      <description>In this article, we will explore the carrying capacity of a 4x4 timber post and understand the factors that influence its load-bearing capabilities. A timber post&amp;rsquo;s capacity to bear weight is not a single, fixed number, but rather depends on various design-specific factors and loading conditions. We will dive into the two main modes of failure for columns – buckling and material yielding – and how they impact the load-carrying capacity of a wooden post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Talking Teak: Understanding the Benefits and Uses of Teak Cladding</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/teak-vs-cedar-cladding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/teak-vs-cedar-cladding/</guid>
      <description>Teak wood has long been admired for its exceptional properties and versatility. In this article, we will delve into the world of teak cladding, exploring its origins, properties, and various applications. Whether you are a DIY enthusiast or a professional woodworker, teak cladding offers a sustainable and durable option for your decking, siding, or furniture projects.
The Origins and Properties of Teak Wood Teak wood, scientifically known as Tectanograndus, is native to India and neighboring Burma.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Finishing All My DIY Outdoor Cedar Furniture Builds with Teak Oil</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/teak-oil-cedar-bench/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/teak-oil-cedar-bench/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this article, we will discuss the process of finishing outdoor cedar furniture builds with teak oil. Cedar wood is a popular choice for outdoor furniture due to its durability and aesthetic appeal. By allowing the furniture to naturally weather and gray out, it develops a beautiful patina over time. Once the desired aging process is achieved, applying teak oil provides protection and enhances the appearance of the furniture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Finishing DIY Outdoor Cedar Furniture with Teak Oil for Long-Lasting Protection</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/oil-to-apply-to-cedar-furniture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/oil-to-apply-to-cedar-furniture/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this article, we will discuss the process of finishing outdoor cedar furniture with teak oil for long-lasting protection. Cedar furniture is a popular choice for outdoor use due to its durability, affordability, and natural beauty. By applying teak oil to the cedar furniture, it not only enhances its appearance but also provides a protective layer against the elements. We will guide you through the step-by-step process of applying teak oil, the benefits of using this type of finish, and tips for maintaining your furniture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Achieve a Perfect Painted Finish on MDF with Sanding Sealer</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/mdf-board-staining/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/mdf-board-staining/</guid>
      <description>MDF, or Medium Density Fiberboard, is a versatile material commonly used in furniture and other household items. However, painting MDF can be a challenge, especially when it comes to achieving a smooth and glossy finish. In this article, we will discuss a simple and effective technique using sanding sealer to create a glass-like finish on MDF.
Key Points: MDF is a cost-effective and easy-to-work-with material that is commonly used in furniture and other household items.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Fix Cloudy Water-Based Polyurethane - The Twisted Pine Woodworking Co.</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-to-fix-cloudy-water-based-polyurethane/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-to-fix-cloudy-water-based-polyurethane/</guid>
      <description>In this article, we will discuss how to fix cloudy water-based polyurethane. If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever applied lacquer over wet wood or used stain that was still a little too wet, you may have encountered the issue of white marks or a cloudy appearance on the surface. This can be frustrating, especially when you want a perfectly stained finish without any blemishes. Fortunately, there is an easy solution to fix this problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> **Boiled Linseed Oil Rags On Fire | Safety and Drying Time For Woodworking Oil Finish**</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-long-does-boiled-linseed-oil-last/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-long-does-boiled-linseed-oil-last/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In the world of woodworking, boiled linseed oil is a popular choice for finishing projects. It provides a beautiful finish and enhances the natural beauty of the wood. However, there are some important safety considerations when working with boiled linseed oil. In this article, we will explore the drying time of boiled linseed oil and the best practices for handling linseed oil rags to avoid fire hazards.
The Danger of Boiled Linseed Oil Rags Linseed oil rags, as well as any oil rag, have the potential to catch fire if not handled properly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> **Can Additional Coats of Rubio Increase Wood Waterproofing?**</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-long-for-rubio-to-dry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-long-for-rubio-to-dry/</guid>
      <description>Welcome back to my channel! Today, I want to share with you an interesting experiment that I conducted to determine if applying additional coats of Rubio Monocoat can increase the waterproofing abilities of wood. Rubio Monocoat is known for its molecular bonding with wood, giving it a unique look and protection. Usually, one coat of Rubio Monocoat is recommended, but I often apply multiple coats without showing it in my videos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Bosch Table Saw: Unveiling the Persistent Flaw in the 1030 and 4100 Series</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/bosch-4100-table-saw-problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/bosch-4100-table-saw-problems/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this article, we will be diving into the persistent flaw found in Bosch table saws, particularly in the 1030 and 4100 series. As a seasoned professional in the woodworking industry, it is crucial to have reliable and efficient tools that can withstand the demands of your work. Unfortunately, some Bosch table saw models have shown a significant flaw that may put their users at a disadvantage. In this in-depth analysis, we will explore the issue, its causes, and possible solutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Achieve a Budget Paint Job Using Rustoleum Paint | Step-by-Step Guide</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/spraying-rustoleum-oil-based-paint/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/spraying-rustoleum-oil-based-paint/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Are you tired of spending a fortune on professional automotive paint jobs? Well, we have good news for you! In this article, we will show you how to mix and spray Rustoleum paint, an economical alternative that can give your car a decent and impressive finish. With just a few simple steps and affordable equipment, you can achieve a budget paint job that will leave your vehicle looking sleek and refreshed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> This Simple Wood Finish Will Save You Days of Shop Time! (Shellac) - The Best Finish for Your Woodworking Projects</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/shellac-dry-on-metal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/shellac-dry-on-metal/</guid>
      <description>In the woodworking world, shellac was once considered the ultimate finish for wood. However, in recent years, the popularity of shellac has waned due to the rise of modern finishes like polyurethane. But what many woodworkers fail to realize is that shellac still has numerous advantages and is a fantastic finish for many projects. In this article, we will delve into the benefits of using shellac, how to apply it properly, and when it is the ideal choice for your woodworking projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Vector Databases: Explained and Their Impact on AI Applications</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/is-pine-good-for-objects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/is-pine-good-for-objects/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In recent years, vector databases have taken the tech industry by storm. These databases, such as Pinecone DB, Chroma, and Weaviate, have attracted significant funding and attention due to their ability to store and query complex objects represented as vectors. In this article, we will explore what vector databases are, how they work, and their impact on various AI-driven applications.
What is a Vector Database? A vector database is a type of database that stores and retrieves arrays of numbers, known as vectors, based on their similarity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>  Step-by-Step Guide on How to Create an Oil Finished Epoxy River Table</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/epoxy-and-oil-finish/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/epoxy-and-oil-finish/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this article, we will walk you through the entire process of creating a stunning metallic black cherry River Bar top using epoxy and an oil finish. We will explain step by step how we transformed a badly cupped and warped live edge slab into a beautiful table, from stripping away the bark to pouring the river and applying the Rubio Monocoat finish. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re looking for tips and tricks or simply want to witness the mesmerizing process of working with epoxy, you&amp;rsquo;ve come to the right place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Comparison and Review: Dewalt vs Porter Cable vs Porter Cable Brushless</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/porter-cable-vs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/porter-cable-vs/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this article, we will be conducting a comparison and review of three impact tools: Dewalt, Porter Cable, and Porter Cable Brushless. These tools are all 20 volts and have been used extensively over the years. We will be examining their performance and evaluating how they stack up against each other. Keep in mind that this review is based on real-world experiences and not on scientific testing.
Key Points Dewalt: The Dewalt impact tool has been in use for approximately six years and has proven to be reliable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Do they really boil linseed oil? Understanding and Choosing Natural Oil Finishes for Woodworking Projects</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/minimum-temperature-for-boiled-linseed-oil/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/minimum-temperature-for-boiled-linseed-oil/</guid>
      <description>Introduction
Natural oil finishes have become incredibly popular amongst hobbyist woodworkers due to their ease of application, durability, and beautiful low luster sheen. However, the market for oil finishes has become saturated with a wide range of products, confusing consumers with various labels and claims. In this article, we will cut through the nonsense and provide you with the knowledge to choose the right oil finish for your next woodworking project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How Strong Are Dowels, Dominos, and Biscuits? A Strength Test</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/dowel-joint-advantages-and-disadvantages/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/dowel-joint-advantages-and-disadvantages/</guid>
      <description>In this article, we will be exploring the strength of different joints - biscuit joints, dowel joints, and domino joints. This experiment follows a previous strength test video where the strength of glue was compared with and without biscuits. The results of that experiment were surprising, so let&amp;rsquo;s dive into this follow-up experiment and see what we discover.
The Experiment For this experiment, the creator used 18 millimeter hardwood plywood as the test material.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Water Damage Repair: Transforming a Buffet into a Stunning Piece of Furniture</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/water-damage-repairs-furniture/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/water-damage-repairs-furniture/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Do you love finding hidden treasures and turning them into beautiful pieces of furniture? Whether you&amp;rsquo;re looking to start a side hustle or furnish your home on a budget, this article is for you. Join me as I tackle a water-damaged buffet and show you the steps to repair it and give it a whole new lease on life.
Assessing the Damage When I first acquired this buffet, it had been left out in the rain for days, resulting in severe water damage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Best Outdoor Wood: Teak, Cedar, or Something Else?!</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/teak-on-cedar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/teak-on-cedar/</guid>
      <description>Introduction When it comes to building outdoor projects, choosing the right wood is crucial. You want a wood that can withstand the elements, from hot summers to cold winters, and everything in between. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore different types of woods that are ideal for outdoor projects and provide recommendations based on their durability, stability, and availability. So, whether you&amp;rsquo;re building a patio table or decking, this guide will help you make an informed decision.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Prepare and Apply Rubio Monocoat to Old Furniture</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/preparation-for-rubio-monocoat-on-old-furniture/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/preparation-for-rubio-monocoat-on-old-furniture/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In recent years, many woodworking enthusiasts have been turning to hard wax oil finishes for their furniture projects. These finishes offer a variety of benefits, including low toxicity, ease of application, and a natural-looking finish. In this article, we will specifically explore how to apply Rubio Monocoat, one of the popular hard wax oil finishes, to old furniture. Whether you are a seasoned woodworker or a novice, this step-by-step guide will help you achieve a perfect finish on your furniture pieces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Is Tung Oil Flammable When Dry: The Hidden Fire Hazard You Need to Know About</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/is-tung-oil-flammable-when-dry/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/is-tung-oil-flammable-when-dry/</guid>
      <description>In recent years, there have been numerous reports of devastating fires starting without a spark. And the surprising culprit? Linseed oil, a commonly used wood stain and sealant found in every hardware store. This seemingly harmless product poses a significant fire hazard, and it&amp;rsquo;s essential to understand the risks associated with it.
Linseed oil is used to preserve wood, providing a protective layer and enhancing its appearance. When applied and spread out, linseed oil is relatively safe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Mixing Stain &amp; Polyurethane: What You Need to Know</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/mixing-stain-and-polyurethane/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/mixing-stain-and-polyurethane/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to finishing wood, there are different methods and products available. One common question many DIY woodworkers have is, &amp;ldquo;What would happen if you mixed oil-based stain with oil-based polyurethane and then applied it to the wood?&amp;rdquo; In today&amp;rsquo;s article, we will explore the results of this experiment and provide insights into whether mixing stain and polyurethane is a viable option.
To conduct this experiment, Alley Picked, a renowned YouTube channel, embarked on a journey to test different combinations of polyurethane and stain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Woodturning Fixing Cracks: How to Fill Cracks in Bowl Blanks</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/filling-cracks-in-bowl-blanks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/filling-cracks-in-bowl-blanks/</guid>
      <description>Subtitle: A comprehensive guide on dealing with and fixing cracks in wood bowl blanks
Have you ever come across those nasty cracks in your wood bowl blanks? Cracks are a common occurrence when turning wood bowls, especially when working with large chunks of wood that have not been commercially dried. Understanding the causes of cracks and learning how to effectively deal with them is essential for woodturners. In this article, we will explore the different types of cracks, the reasons behind them, and three effective methods for filling cracks and holes in your bowls to create aesthetically pleasing and structurally sound pieces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> **Bow Saw vs Carpenter Saw: A Comparison of Tools for Outdoor Use**</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/carpenter-saw-vs-bow-saw/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/carpenter-saw-vs-bow-saw/</guid>
      <description>In this article, we will be discussing the differences between a bow saw and a carpenter saw, specifically in the context of outdoor use. Many people may wonder which saw is more suitable for cutting wood and completing various tasks while in the great outdoors. Whether you are a seasoned woodworker or someone who enjoys camping and DIY projects, it is crucial to understand the capabilities and limitations of each tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> What Are the Benefits of Using Hemlock Lumber?</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/is-hemlock-rot-resistant/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/is-hemlock-rot-resistant/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Hemlock lumber is a popular choice for building projects due to its unique properties. In this article, we will explore the advantages of using hemlock in construction. Whether you are in the middle of a project or trying to make an informed decision about the best type of lumber to use, this information will help you understand why hemlock may be the right choice for your needs.
Pros of Using Hemlock 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> A Comprehensive Guide to Cedar Wood: One of the Most Versatile and Resilient Woods</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/is-hemlock-or-cedar-harder/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/is-hemlock-or-cedar-harder/</guid>
      <description>Cedar wood is known for its distinctive smell and exceptional properties that have made it a highly sought-after material throughout history. Used in various applications, from construction to furniture making, cedar offers durability, resistance to rot and insects, and a unique aesthetic appeal. In this article, we will explore the characteristics of cedar wood, its uses, and some important considerations when working with it.
Understanding True Cedar and False Cedar Contrary to popular belief, there are only four species of true cedars in the world, with three found in the Mediterranean region and one in the Himalayas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> A Guide to Applying Oil Finishes Correctly</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/tung-oil-thinner/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/tung-oil-thinner/</guid>
      <description>In recent years, natural oils have gained popularity as a safe and effective way to finish wood. These oils not only provide a beautiful finish, but they also offer excellent water resistance. However, if applied incorrectly, they can lead to a sticky mess. In this article, we will discuss the correct way to apply oil finishes, focusing on tung oil and its application process. By following the steps outlined below, you can achieve a flawless finish every time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Avoid Tearout With This Simple Trick: How to Prevent Tearout When Sawing a Board</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/preventing-tear-out-when-sawing-a-board/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/preventing-tear-out-when-sawing-a-board/</guid>
      <description>Woodworking is a delicate craft that requires precision and care. One common issue that woodworkers face is tear-out, which happens when the blade pulls the grain and causes splintering at the cut point. To avoid this problem, many woodworkers use zero-clearance inserts and sacrificial fences to support the fibers. However, there is a better way to prevent tear-out, inspired by an old-school methodology. In this article, we will explore a simple trick that can help you achieve clean and crisp cuts without the hassle of tear-out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> SawStop 3 HP Industrial Cabinet Saw Unboxing and Assembly Guide</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/sawstop-industrial-vs-professional/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/sawstop-industrial-vs-professional/</guid>
      <description>In this article, we will guide you through the process of unboxing and setting up the SawStop 3 HP Industrial Cabinet Saw. This powerful saw is a valuable addition to any woodworking shop, and we will provide step-by-step instructions to ensure a smooth assembly process.
Before we dive into the assembly process, it is essential to read the owner&amp;rsquo;s manual thoroughly. The manual contains detailed instructions that will help you throughout the assembly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Do You Really Need Wood Conditioner When Staining? Achieve the Perfect Finish!</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/soft-or-hard-water-aspen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/soft-or-hard-water-aspen/</guid>
      <description>Many DIY enthusiasts and woodworkers often come across the dilemma of whether they should use a wood conditioner when staining their projects. The back of stain containers often recommends using a wood conditioner, but is it really necessary? In this article, we will conduct a test using a pine board to determine if using a wood conditioner, water, or no conditioner at all produces the best finish. Stay tuned to find out the results and make an informed decision for your next staining project!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Cut an Angled Square Hole in Wood: Mastering the Mortise and Tenon Joint</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-to-cut-angled-square-hole-in-wood/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-to-cut-angled-square-hole-in-wood/</guid>
      <description>Woodworking enthusiasts know the importance of strong and durable joints, and one of the most reliable joints in the craft is the mortise and tenon joint. To build furniture that will last, learning how to create square holes, or mortises, is essential. While most methods involve using a drill press, this article will guide you on how to achieve the same results using basic tools, particularly a round forstner drill bit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Using Wood Glue as a Sealant: A Quick Tip by Mike Thompson</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/does-wood-glue-work-paint/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/does-wood-glue-work-paint/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this article, we will discuss a quick tip shared by Mike Thompson regarding the use of wood glue as a sealant. If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever struggled with sealing porous surfaces like MDF or needed a solution for styrofoam that is resistant to bondo, this tip might just be the answer you&amp;rsquo;re looking for.
How to Use Wood Glue as a Sealant Assess the Surface: Before using wood glue as a sealant, it is important to assess the surface you&amp;rsquo;ll be working on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> What Is S-P-F LUMBER? Understanding the Difference Between S-P-F and SYP</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-is-southern-yellow-pine-good-for-construction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-is-southern-yellow-pine-good-for-construction/</guid>
      <description>Introduction
When visiting a lumber yard, you may have noticed the letters &amp;ldquo;SPF&amp;rdquo; stamped on the wood. These letters stand for spruce, pine, and fir, which are three types of trees commonly used in construction. In this article, we will explore the meaning behind these letters, the qualities of SPF lumber, and its alternatives. Additionally, we will discuss the difference between SPF and Southern Yellow Pine (SYP), another popular choice in the construction industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Are Table Saws Becoming Obsolete in Woodworking? </title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/is-a-table-saw-necessary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/is-a-table-saw-necessary/</guid>
      <description>Is a table saw necessary in today&amp;rsquo;s world of track saws and edge guides? Can&amp;rsquo;t you accomplish all your cuts with other tools like a miter saw, circular saw, and router table? In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll debunk the myth that table saws are becoming obsolete and explore the reasons why they remain a critical and versatile tool in the woodworking workshop.
It&amp;rsquo;s a common question that arises during discussions about woodworking tools - are table saws becoming obsolete?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Stain MDF Wood: A Comprehensive Guide for Beginners</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/stained-mdf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/stained-mdf/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Staining MDF wood can be a daunting task, especially if you&amp;rsquo;re new to it. However, with a good understanding of the process and some basic techniques, you can achieve professional-looking results. In this article, we will guide you through the steps of staining MDF wood, using the expert advice shared in a Youtube video by Maximus Spaniard.
Preparing for Staining Before you begin staining, make sure the MDF wood is clean and free from dust.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Pros and Cons of Metal Bed Frames vs. Wooden Bed Frames</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/pros-and-cons-of-metal-bed-frame/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/pros-and-cons-of-metal-bed-frame/</guid>
      <description>Choosing the right bed frame is an important decision as we spend more than a third of our lives sleeping. When considering buying a bed, there are several factors to take into account such as cost, material, and size. The most common bed frames are made either from wood or metal. This article will explore the pros and cons of metal bed frames and wooden bed frames to help you make an informed decision.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Does Minwax Wood Hardener Actually Harden Wood?</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-you-harden-soft-wood/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-you-harden-soft-wood/</guid>
      <description>Wood hardeners are products designed to strengthen and reinforce wood that may be weak, rotted, or damaged. One popular brand of wood hardener is Minwax Wood Hardener. But does it actually live up to its name? In this article, we will explore the effectiveness of Minwax Wood Hardener in hardening wood and discuss the results of a test conducted by Shawn in his workshop.
What&amp;rsquo;s Left Behind After Evaporation Minwax Wood Hardener is a form of plastic dissolved in a solvent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Mirka Deros vs Festool ETS EC | The Ultimate Sander Comparison</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/festool-vs-mirka/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/festool-vs-mirka/</guid>
      <description>Introduction:
In the market for a premium sander? Look no further! In this article, we will be comparing two top contenders: the Mirka Deros and the Festool ETS EC150. Both sanders are known for their exceptional performance and quality, but is the extra price tag on the Mirka worth it? Let&amp;rsquo;s dive in and find out!
Before we get started, it&amp;rsquo;s important to note that the author has been using a Festool sander for over a decade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Preventing and Healing Cracked Fingertips: A Complete Guide</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/prevent-splits-and-cracks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/prevent-splits-and-cracks/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Are you familiar with the pain and discomfort of cracked fingertips? These small cracks in the skin can be incredibly painful, but the good news is that they are relatively easy to fix using common items found in your medicine cabinet. In this article, we will explore the causes of cracked fingertips and discuss step-by-step methods for preventing and healing them. We will also delve into the science behind this common issue, allowing you to better understand how these methods work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> The Fast and Easy Method for a Smooth Finish with Spray Lacquer on Your Kitchen Table</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/spray-lacquer-on-kitchen-table/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/spray-lacquer-on-kitchen-table/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to adding a beautiful finish to your woodworking projects, lacquer is a popular choice. In particular, spray lacquer offers a fast and easy method to achieve a smooth and fantastic-looking finish. In this article, we will explore the benefits of using spray lacquer, step-by-step instructions on how to apply it, and tips for achieving a professional finish.
Why Choose Spray Lacquer? Spray lacquer, which comes in a convenient spray can, offers several advantages over other types of finishes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> What to Consider When Staining MDF Boards: Tips and Techniques</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-you-stain-mdf-board/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-you-stain-mdf-board/</guid>
      <description>While MDF (Medium Density Fiberboard) wood is lightweight and strong, it can be susceptible to damage from moisture and condensation. When a wet object, like a soda can, is placed on MDF, it can create a ring that may cause the wood to bubble up. Whether you are new to working with MDF or have been building models for a while, it is important to use the right techniques and products to ensure a clean and durable finish for your projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Wooden Cutting Boards: A Guide to Preventing Cracking and Maintenance</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/oil-to-prevent-wood-from-cracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/oil-to-prevent-wood-from-cracking/</guid>
      <description>Wooden cutting boards are a staple in many kitchens due to their durability and aesthetic appeal. However, without proper maintenance, these boards can crack and become unusable. In this article, we will discuss the importance of caring for wooden cutting boards and provide step-by-step instructions on how to properly maintain them. By following these guidelines, you can ensure that your cutting board remains in excellent condition for years to come.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> **Do You Need to Sand Between Coats of Paint? - A Comprehensive Guide**</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/sanding-oil-based-paint-after-first-coat-grit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/sanding-oil-based-paint-after-first-coat-grit/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to painting a surface, there are many factors to consider to achieve a smooth and flawless finish. One question that often arises is whether it is necessary to sand between coats of paint. In this article, we will delve into this topic and provide you with a comprehensive guide on when and how to sand between coats of paint.
Understanding the Importance of Sanding Between Coats of Paint Sanding between coats of paint plays a crucial role in achieving a professional finish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Apply Linseed Oil on Wood: Testing Durability and Waterproofing </title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/linseed-oil-on-cedar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/linseed-oil-on-cedar/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this article, we will explore the process of applying linseed oil on wood and examine its durability and waterproofing capabilities. Linseed oil is a natural finish that is commonly used to enhance the appearance and protect wooden surfaces. We will provide you with step-by-step instructions on how to apply linseed oil and discuss the results of our durability tests. So let&amp;rsquo;s dive into the world of linseed oil!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Create Rounded Edges on Woodworking Projects: A Step-by-Step Guide</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-to-make-rounded-edges-without-router/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-to-make-rounded-edges-without-router/</guid>
      <description>For woodworking enthusiasts, the finishing touches can make all the difference in the final outcome of their projects. One crucial detail that often gets overlooked is the softening or breaking of edges. Breaking edges refers to the process of rounding off the sharp corners and edges on a workpiece, and it serves both functional and aesthetic purposes. In this article, we will explore the reasons behind breaking edges, different tools that can be used, and step-by-step instructions on how to achieve the desired result.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> The secret to achieving a flawless finish with spray lacquer in under 30 minutes | A comprehensive guide to wood finishing</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-many-coats-of-lacquer-should-i-apply-to-wood/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-many-coats-of-lacquer-should-i-apply-to-wood/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Welcome to another episode of the ABCs of Woodworking! In today&amp;rsquo;s segment, we&amp;rsquo;ll be discussing &amp;ldquo;L&amp;rdquo; for lacquer. Specifically, we&amp;rsquo;ll focus on spray lacquer, which offers a fast and easy method for achieving a smooth and fantastic-looking finish on your woodworking projects. While there are other options like brushing lacquer, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore the benefits of spray lacquer and the steps to apply it effectively.
The Advantages of Spray Lacquer Spray lacquer, despite its higher cost, offers numerous advantages that make it a popular choice among woodworkers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>  How to Build Barn Doors that Will Never Warp | The Ninja Woodworker&#39;s Guide</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/build-barn-doors-will-not-warp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/build-barn-doors-will-not-warp/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Building a wooden door that is strong, sturdy, and resistant to warping can be a challenging task. However, in this article, we will explore a step-by-step guide on how to create a barn door with floating panels. By following these instructions, you can ensure that your wooden door will never warp, and you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to impress your clients with your woodworking skills. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive in!
Key Points: The Ninja Woodworker&amp;rsquo;s tight deadline challenge:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> **Siberian Elm: A Versatile Hardwood for Furniture and More**</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/is-siberian-elm-a-hardwood/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/is-siberian-elm-a-hardwood/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Baldwin Hardwoods&amp;rsquo; Lumber Education Series! In this article, we will explore the unique characteristics of Siberian elm, a locally produced hardwood known for its distinct grain patterns and versatile uses. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a woodworking enthusiast or simply curious about different types of lumber, this article is your guide to understanding and appreciating Siberian elm.
What Sets Siberian Elm Apart Siberian elm stands out among other hardwood species due to its sourcing process and distinctive features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Prevent Bed Slats from Sliding Off: A Simple Fix for a Common Problem</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/bed-slats-keep-falling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/bed-slats-keep-falling/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Have you ever encountered the frustrating issue of bed slats constantly sliding off, causing your bed to sink and become unstable? If you have, you&amp;rsquo;re not alone. Many people with beds that have slats, such as those from IKEA, often face this problem. However, there is a simple and inexpensive solution to this issue that can save you from the inconvenience and discomfort. In this article, we will show you how to fix bed slats from sliding off using a clever DIY hack involving Velcro stickers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Teak Oil Restoration: How Effective is it? A Detailed Review</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/drying-time-teak-oil/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/drying-time-teak-oil/</guid>
      <description>Teak furniture is known for its durability and beauty, but over time, it can start to lose its charm and develop a gray, aged look. To combat this, there are various products available in the market that promise to restore your teak furniture to its former glory. One such product is Bayes Teak Cleaner and Restoration Oil, which has received rave reviews on Amazon. In this article, we will delve into the effectiveness of teak oil restoration and see if Bayes Teak Cleaner and Restoration Oil lives up to its claims.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Increasing the Crosscut Capacity of a 10 Miter Saw for Laminate Flooring Installation</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-wide-of-a-board-can-a-10-miter-saw-cut/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-wide-of-a-board-can-a-10-miter-saw-cut/</guid>
      <description>Learn how to increase the crosscut capacity of a 10-inch miter saw to accommodate wider laminate flooring planks.
Are you in the middle of a laminate flooring installation project but your 10-inch miter saw can only crosscut up to six inches? Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to invest in a new saw just yet. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll guide you through a temporary modification to increase the crosscut capacity of your 10-inch miter saw to at least eight inches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Mirka Deros and Extractor: Unveiling the Best Sanding System</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/mirkas-ha-gas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/mirkas-ha-gas/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Are you tired of using heavy and cumbersome sanders that don&amp;rsquo;t deliver the desired results? Look no further - the Mirka Deros and Extractor are here to revolutionize your sanding experience. In this comprehensive review and comparison, we&amp;rsquo;ll dive deep into the key features and benefits of this exceptional sanding system. With its balance, user comfort, and unparalleled finish quality, the Mirka Deros and Extractor are the go-to choice for both professionals and DIY enthusiasts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Why I Chose a Laguna Table Saw Instead of SawStop: A Detailed Review</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/sawstop-vs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/sawstop-vs/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this article, we will discuss my decision to purchase a Laguna table saw over a SawStop, debunking the myth that only serious woodworkers must own a SawStop. I will provide detailed insights into why I chose Laguna and explain the factors that influenced my decision.
Background I recently moved my woodworking shop from Texas to Ohio, and during this transition, I wanted to upgrade my table saw. Initially, I had a Delta 36-725 contractor saw, which I loved due to its affordability and practicality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Best Finish for Cornhole Boards of 2023: Protecting Your Game Investment</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/best-coating-for-cornhole-boards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/best-coating-for-cornhole-boards/</guid>
      <description>Cornhole is a popular outdoor game that brings friends and family together for hours of fun and friendly competition. If you&amp;rsquo;re an avid cornhole player, you likely have your own set of cornhole boards. While these boards come in various designs and materials, they all require a protective finish to ensure their longevity and performance. In this article, we will discuss the best finishes for cornhole boards in 2023, so you can make an informed decision and protect your investment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Use Any Brand Battery in Any Power Tool: A Game Changer for DIY Enthusiasts</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-you-use-drill-batteries-on-other-brands/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-you-use-drill-batteries-on-other-brands/</guid>
      <description>As DIY enthusiasts, we often face the dilemma of wanting to add new tools to our collection but not wanting to invest in a new battery platform. We may already have a favorite brand that we&amp;rsquo;re loyal to and don&amp;rsquo;t want to switch. However, what if there was a way to use any brand of battery in any power tool? Well, it turns out there is!
In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore the world of battery adapters that allow you to use different brands of batteries in any power tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Water Damaged Buffet | How to Restore Water Damaged Furniture</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/water-damaged-furniture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/water-damaged-furniture/</guid>
      <description>Are you someone who loves finding and fixing up old furniture? Whether you&amp;rsquo;re looking to start a side hustle or just want to furnish your home on a budget, this article is for you. In this article, we will show you how to restore water damaged furniture, specifically a water damaged buffet. We will walk you through the step-by-step process of repairing the damage and giving new life to a piece of furniture that was headed for the landfill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>  Understanding Janka Hardness of Southern Yellow Pine</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/janka-hardness-of-southern-yellow-pine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/janka-hardness-of-southern-yellow-pine/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this article, we will discuss the Janka hardness of Southern Yellow Pine, a popular wood used in various applications. We will explore the characteristics of Southern Yellow Pine, its uses, and why understanding its Janka hardness is important for anyone working with wood. If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in woodworking or want to learn more about this versatile material, keep reading!
What is Janka Hardness? Janka hardness is a measure of a wood&amp;rsquo;s resistance to indentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> An Expert Guide to Zinsser Cover Stain®: The Ultimate Solution for Stains and Sealers</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-you-stain-over-zinsser/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-you-stain-over-zinsser/</guid>
      <description>Zinsser Cover Stain® is an all-purpose white solvent-based stain-killing primer sealer that is revolutionizing the world of interior and exterior painting. With its exceptional stain-blocking and sealing properties, this product is a must-have for both professionals and DIY enthusiasts.
Key Points: Zinsser Cover Stain® is a versatile primer sealer suitable for both interior and exterior applications. It can be used under any solvent-based or water-based topcoat, making it incredibly versatile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Use Polycrylic to Finish Your Acrylic Pour Paintings: Step-by-Step Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-you-paint-over-polycrylic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-you-paint-over-polycrylic/</guid>
      <description>Welcome back to another episode of Meta Pours Fluid Art, where we explore different techniques and methods for creating stunning acrylic pour paintings. In today&amp;rsquo;s tutorial, we will be discussing how to finish your acrylic pour paintings using Polycrylic. This varnish is my preferred method for sealing and protecting my canvases, and I am excited to share this step-by-step process with you.
The Benefits of Using Polycrylic Polycrylic is a fantastic choice for finishing your acrylic pour paintings for several reasons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Is Waterlox Safe for Wood Tables? Understanding Food-Safe Wood Finishes</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/is-waterlox-safe-for-wood-tables/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/is-waterlox-safe-for-wood-tables/</guid>
      <description>Wood finishes are a common concern for many when it comes to the safety of their furniture and kitchen items. People often wonder if the finishes they use on their wooden tables, countertops, and even cutting boards are food-safe. In this article, we will explore the truth behind food-safe wood finishes and debunk some common misconceptions.
Marketing terms, such as &amp;ldquo;food-safe,&amp;rdquo; used by some manufacturers to label their finishes can be misleading.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Use New Batteries on Old Makita Tools: A Handy Trick for Workshop Enthusiasts</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/new-makita-battery-on-old-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/new-makita-battery-on-old-tool/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In the world of power tools, Makita is a well-known and highly respected brand. Over time, technology advances and with it, the development of newer, more powerful batteries. However, this can pose a challenge for owners of older Makita tools, as the new batteries may not be compatible with their equipment. This article will explore a clever trick to overcome this compatibility issue, enabling the use of new batteries on old Makita tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Alumilite Explains: Understanding the Differences Between Epoxy, Polyurethane, and Resin</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-polyurethane-be-applied-to-epoxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-polyurethane-be-applied-to-epoxy/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to working with resins, it&amp;rsquo;s important to understand the differences between epoxy, polyurethane, and resin. In this article, we will dive into the world of resins and explore what sets them apart from each other. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a professional or a DIY enthusiast, having this knowledge will help you make informed decisions for your projects.
Resin, as a term, is quite broad. There are organic resins like gums produced by trees, but in this context, we&amp;rsquo;ll focus on synthetic resins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Choose the Best Finish for Outdoor Projects: A Comprehensive Guide</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/is-oak-good-for-outdoor-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/is-oak-good-for-outdoor-use/</guid>
      <description>As an expert copywriter and a woodworking enthusiast, I understand the importance of choosing the right finish for outdoor projects. It&amp;rsquo;s a decision that requires careful consideration and understanding of the available options. In this article, I will guide you through the process of choosing the best finish for your outdoor projects, focusing on the use of oak wood. Oak is known for its durability and natural beauty, making it a popular choice for outdoor applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Glue Wood Edge to Edge Without a Router</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-to-glue-wood-edge-to-edge-without-a-router/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-to-glue-wood-edge-to-edge-without-a-router/</guid>
      <description>Woodworking is a skill that requires careful attention to detail and precision. One common challenge that woodworkers face is joining wood edges together without using a jointer. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a beginner or an experienced woodworker, knowing alternative techniques for edge jointing can come in handy.
There are several reasons why you might need to use these techniques. If you&amp;rsquo;re new to woodworking, you might find yourself purchasing pre-planed wood from a supplier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Soften Wood for Woodcarving: Tips and Techniques</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/solution-to-softening-wood-for-carving/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/solution-to-softening-wood-for-carving/</guid>
      <description>Image: Woodcarving-Chisel-Pieces.jpg
Woodcarving is a popular hobby that requires skill and precision. One important aspect of woodcarving is having the right type of wood, which should be soft enough to make carving easier. In this article, we will discuss different techniques and solutions to soften wood for woodcarving. Whether you are a beginner or an experienced woodcarver, these tips will help you achieve the desired level of softness in your wood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Should You Buy a Miter Saw? - A Beginner Woodworker&#39;s Guide</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/should-i-get-a-10-or-12-miter-saw/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/should-i-get-a-10-or-12-miter-saw/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In the world of woodworking, having the right tools is essential for efficient and precise work. One tool that often sparks debate among woodworkers is the miter saw. Some swear by its usefulness, while others question its necessity. In this article, we will explore the value of keeping a miter saw in the shop and help beginners make an informed decision about whether they should buy one.
Breaking Down Rough Lumber One of the most common reasons people advocate for a miter saw is its ability to quickly and safely break down rough lumber.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Choose the Right Miter Saw for Your Woodworking Projects </title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/miter-saw-10-or-12-inch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/miter-saw-10-or-12-inch/</guid>
      <description>Introduction When it comes to making precise cross cuts or angle cuts on wood or composite materials for projects like baseboards and door frames, a miter saw is an essential tool. However, with various types and sizes available in the market, it can be challenging to determine which one is the right fit for your needs. This article will guide you through the process of choosing the perfect miter saw, highlighting the key features and considerations when making your decision.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Slide Saw vs Cabinet Table Saw: The Advantages of a Slide Saw</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/sliding-table-saw-vs-table-saw/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/sliding-table-saw-vs-table-saw/</guid>
      <description>In the world of woodworking, having the right tools can make all the difference. One tool that has gained popularity among craftsmen is the slide saw, also known as a sliding table saw. In this article, we will explore the top reasons why a slide saw is a better choice over a traditional cabinet table saw for your woodworking projects.
Perfectly Straight Long Glue Line Cuts One of the main advantages of a slide saw is its ability to make perfectly straight long glue line cuts, even on live edge or crooked lumber.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Varathane vs Minwax - Which to Choose?</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/minwax-vs-varathane-polyurethane/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/minwax-vs-varathane-polyurethane/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re in the market for polyurethane products, you&amp;rsquo;ve probably come across the names Varathane and Minwax. These two brands have established themselves as top players in the industry, and for good reason. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll dive into the differences between Varathane and Minwax, and help you decide which brand is right for you.
Varathane: A Storied Reputation Varathane, which has been producing wood finishing products since 1958, is known for its high-quality offerings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>  The Advantages and Uses of Shellac Wood Finish: A Simple Solution to Save Time</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/lacquer-over-shellac/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/lacquer-over-shellac/</guid>
      <description>Shellac: The Simple and Efficient Wood Finish for Saving Time in Your Workshop
Introduction Wood finish options are plentiful, but one classic option that often gets overlooked is shellac. In the past, shellac was considered the best finish for wood, but modern finishes like polyurethane have taken over the market. However, shellac still holds many advantages that make it worth considering. In this article, we will explore why you should be using shellac, how to use it, and when it is the ideal choice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Best Clear Cedar Finish for Outdoors in 2023: Protecting and Beautifying Your Cedar Wood</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/sealer-finish-for-outdoor-cedar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/sealer-finish-for-outdoor-cedar/</guid>
      <description>Cedar wood is a popular choice for outdoor projects due to its natural beauty and its ability to resist bacteria and fungus. However, to ensure its longevity and protect it from insects, mold, and mildew, it is necessary to apply a clear cedar finish. In this article, we will explore the five best clear cedar finishes for outdoors in 2023 and discuss their features, pros, and cons.
1. Minwax 63210444 Clear Cedar Finish for Outdoors One of the top choices for clear cedar finishes is the Minwax 63210444.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Finishing Your Coasters: A Guide to Using Sealant for Wood Coasters</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/sealant-for-wood-coasters/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/sealant-for-wood-coasters/</guid>
      <description>Wooden coasters are a popular choice for adding a touch of elegance to any home decor. Whether you have purchased or handmade your coasters, it is crucial to protect them from potential damage caused by wet drinks. In this article, we will guide you through the process of sealing your wood coasters using a spray-on polyurethane sealant. This clear satin or clear matte sealant not only enhances the appearance of your coasters but also provides a protective layer to ensure their longevity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Linseed Oil: A Hidden Fire Hazard Found in Every Hardware Store</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/heated-polymerized-linseed-oil/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/heated-polymerized-linseed-oil/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In recent times, we have been witnessing devastating fires occurring in homes and restaurants across America, and the cause behind these fires is quite surprising. It turns out that a very common product found in every hardware store, linseed oil, is posing a significant fire hazard. In this article, we will explore the danger of linseed oil, its properties, and how it can lead to spontaneous combustion. We will also discuss safety measures that can be taken to prevent such incidents from occurring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Table Saw Rip Capacity: Increase Table Saw Cut Width for Next to Nothing!</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/left-right-rip-capacity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/left-right-rip-capacity/</guid>
      <description>Introduction
In this article, we will discuss how to increase the rip capacity of a table saw. Many woodworkers often find themselves in need of more cutting space on their table saws, and in this tutorial, we will show you how to add four inches of capacity for almost no cost at all. By following this simple step-by-step process, you can easily expand the cutting width of your table saw and achieve the desired results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Tutorial: How to Safely Drill Holes in Glass for Misting Systems</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/screwing-glass-to-wood/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/screwing-glass-to-wood/</guid>
      <description>Glass is a delicate material that requires special care when drilling to avoid breakage. In this tutorial, we will guide you through the process of drilling holes in glass to accommodate misting systems. Whether you are a DIY enthusiast or a professional, this step-by-step guide will help you successfully secure glass to wood without any mishaps.
Key Points: Tools Needed: To complete this task, you will need the following tools:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> **Choosing the Right Wood for a Cutting Board: A Comprehensive Guide**</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-you-use-hickory-for-a-cutting-board/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-you-use-hickory-for-a-cutting-board/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to making a cutting board, selecting the right type of wood is crucial. The choice of wood can significantly impact the durability, aesthetics, and functionality of the final product. In this article, we will discuss which woods are best suited for cutting boards and which ones should be avoided. So if you&amp;rsquo;re planning to make a cutting board, keep reading to find out which wood to use and which wood to steer clear of.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> 5 Hardwoods That Are Better Than Pine: The Affordable and Versatile Options</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/alder-wood-vs-oak/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/alder-wood-vs-oak/</guid>
      <description>Introduction When starting out in woodworking, going to a wood store can be overwhelming. With a wide range of woods and terminology that may be unfamiliar, making an informed choice can be a challenge. In this article, we will explore five hardwood options that are not only better suited for furniture and decorative home woodworking projects, but also affordable and versatile. These woods include soft maple, poplar, beech, knotty alder, and white oak.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> STOP Wood Warping BEFORE and AFTER Building! Woodworking Tips and Tricks</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/plywood-least-likely-to-warp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/plywood-least-likely-to-warp/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Warped or twisted wood can be a major frustration for woodworkers. Not only does it affect the appearance of the finished project, but it can also undermine the structural integrity. In this article, we will discuss effective strategies for preventing wood from warping. By following these tips and tricks, you can ensure that your lumber remains straight and stable, both before and after building.
Key Points Selecting the Right Lumber: When choosing lumber at the store, look for boards that are free from visible defects like knots or dark stripes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> The Best Way to Treat Cedar Without Coloration: Sealing Natural Wood</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/best-way-to-treat-cedar-without-coloration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/best-way-to-treat-cedar-without-coloration/</guid>
      <description>Introduction When it comes to preserving the natural beauty of wood, sealing is essential. However, many people struggle to find the perfect sealant that won&amp;rsquo;t darken or change the color of the wood. In this article, we will explore the various products available in the market and determine the best way to treat cedar without any coloration.
Finding the Right Products The first step in finding the best sealant is to identify the products that are easily accessible and suitable for this purpose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>  The Magic of Step Drills: Mastering the Art of Drilling Holes in Metal</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/drilling-holes-with-a-step-bit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/drilling-holes-with-a-step-bit/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Drilling holes in metal can be a daunting task, especially when you need to go beyond the quarter-inch limit. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re building an airplane or working with sheet metal, you&amp;rsquo;ll often find yourself in need of larger holes. Luckily, step drills are here to save the day! These versatile tools offer a wide range of hole sizes and are incredibly easy to use. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore the intricacies of step drills and how they can revolutionize your metalworking projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Can You Use Baltic Birch Plywood For Exterior Projects?</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/waterproof-baltic-birch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/waterproof-baltic-birch/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to selecting the right material for outdoor projects, durability and weather resistance are crucial factors to consider. In this article, we will explore the suitability of Baltic birch plywood for exterior applications. Baltic birch plywood is known for its strength and stability, but is it a viable option for outdoor use? Let&amp;rsquo;s dive into a test conducted by John Heisz, a well-known expert in woodworking and creator of the YouTube channel &amp;ldquo;Speakers and Audio Projects&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Dewalt Lithium Ion Battery Won&#39;t Charge? Try This Easy Fix for a Quick Reset</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/dewalt-battery-not-charging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/dewalt-battery-not-charging/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever found yourself with a Dewalt lithium-ion battery that simply refuses to charge, don&amp;rsquo;t worry - we&amp;rsquo;ve got you covered. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll show you a simple fix that will reset your battery and get it back to accepting a charge in no time.
Lithium-ion batteries, like the one from Dewalt that we&amp;rsquo;ll be focusing on, can sometimes become completely depleted and need to be reset in order to begin recharging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How Long Does Beeswax Last: A Guide to Candle Curing</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-long-does-beeswax-last/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-long-does-beeswax-last/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Have you ever wondered how long your candles need to cure before they&amp;rsquo;re ready to use? This age-old question has puzzled many candle makers and enthusiasts. In this article, we will delve into the world of candle curing and explore the factors that affect the curing process. Whether you use 100% soy wax, paraffin wax, or a blend of natural waxes, we will provide you with the information you need to achieve the best burn performance and fragrance throw.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Achieve a Perfect Finish with Benjamin Moore Command Paint - FUJI HVLP</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/sprayer-latex-with-fuji-hvlp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/sprayer-latex-with-fuji-hvlp/</guid>
      <description>Introduction
In this article, we will discuss how to achieve a flawless finish using Benjamin Moore Command paint with a FUJI HVLP sprayer. Benjamin Moore Command paint is known for its fast dry time and durable finish. By following the steps outlined in this guide, you can ensure a professional-quality result every time. So let&amp;rsquo;s dive in and discover the secrets to spraying Benjamin Moore Command paint with a FUJI HVLP sprayer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Straighten Wood for a Barn Door: Fixing a Poor Design</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-to-straighten-wood-for-a-barn-door/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/how-to-straighten-wood-for-a-barn-door/</guid>
      <description>Wood movement can be a destructive force if proper allowances and planning are not made. In this video, we will explore a poorly designed barn door and discuss how to fix it. By analyzing the original joinery and executing a solid repair, we can salvage the door and create a beautiful, functional piece.
Key Points:
Understanding wood movement: Wood is a living material that expands and contracts with changes in humidity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Step Aside, Rubio: The New Era of Hardwax Oils</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/rubio-monocoat-ingredients/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/rubio-monocoat-ingredients/</guid>
      <description>Introduction and the Rise of Hard Wax Oils In the past decade, hard wax oils have gained immense popularity among woodworkers. The ease of application and appealing finish that these oils provide make them highly sought after. Traditionally, Rubio Monocoat has been the dominant player in the market, especially in the United States, with its two-component finishes containing a hardener. However, over the past year, several new competitors have emerged, including Natura Onecoat, Rustic Wood Finish, General Finishes, and Osmo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Baltic Birch Plywood: The Versatile and Durable Furniture Board [Video 518]</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/birch-plywood-facts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/birch-plywood-facts/</guid>
      <description>Baltic Birch plywood, also known as Birch plywood, is a versatile man-made board that is widely used in cabinet making, furniture construction, and woodworking projects. It has gained popularity among professionals and enthusiasts alike for its aesthetic appeal and durability. In this article, we will explore the key features and benefits of Baltic Birch plywood, as well as its current availability and alternatives in the market.
Key Points
Baltic Birch plywood is a versatile man-made board commonly used in cabinet making and furniture construction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Build a Hickory Farmhouse Apron Table with Metal X Legs</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/furniture-making-hickory-limbs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/furniture-making-hickory-limbs/</guid>
      <description>In this article, we will go through the step-by-step process of building a beautiful Hickory Farmhouse Apron Table with Metal X Legs. This table is a stunning addition to any space and is built to last. We will discuss the materials and tools needed, as well as provide detailed instructions on each stage of the building process. So let&amp;rsquo;s dive in and learn how to create this impressive piece of furniture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Proper Way to Tip a Lawn Mower Over: Maintenance and Repairs Made Easy</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-you-put-a-smaller-blade-on-a-lawn-mower/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/can-you-put-a-smaller-blade-on-a-lawn-mower/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Tipping a lawnmower over properly is a common issue that generates a lot of controversy on the internet. Many people struggle with knowing the best method to flip their lawnmowers in order to access the underside of the deck for general maintenance and repairs. In this article, we will provide expert advice on the proper way to tip a lawnmower over. By following our step-by-step process, you can ensure that your lawnmower remains in excellent condition without any damage or complications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Real Reviews - Dewalt vs Porter Cable: A Comparison and Review of Impact Drivers</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/porter-cable-vs-dewalt-impact-driver/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/porter-cable-vs-dewalt-impact-driver/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Do you find yourself in need of a powerful impact driver for your DIY projects or professional tasks? In this article, we will be comparing and reviewing the Dewalt and Porter Cable impact drivers. Specifically, we will be looking at the performance of the Dewalt impact driver, the older Porter Cable model, and the newer brushless Porter Cable model.
Dewalt Impact Driver We&amp;rsquo;ll start with the Dewalt impact driver, which the author has owned for several years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Wood Carving Made Easy: Tips to Soften Wood for Beginners</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/soak-wood-carving/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/soak-wood-carving/</guid>
      <description>Wood carving can be a fulfilling and creative hobby, but it&amp;rsquo;s not always easy, especially when working with harder types of wood like oak or ash. As a beginner wood carver or whittler, you may find yourself struggling to make clean and smooth cuts. In this article, we will explore different methods to make wood easier to carve, so you can enjoy the craftsmanship without the frustration.
Choosing the Right Wood and Knife Before we dive into the techniques for softening wood, it&amp;rsquo;s important to start with the right materials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Achieve a Beautiful Finish with Rubio Monocoat</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/rubio-monocoat-temperature/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/rubio-monocoat-temperature/</guid>
      <description>Image: a finished bench top made with Rubio Monocoat
If you&amp;rsquo;re looking to achieve a stunning finish on your wooden furniture, look no further than Rubio Monocoat. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll take a closer look at how to use Rubio Monocoat and discover the easy steps involved in creating a beautiful, polished look. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a seasoned woodworker or just starting out, Rubio Monocoat is an excellent choice for finishing your furniture pieces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Natural Alternative to Paint for Wood Siding: Protect and Beautify your Home with Linseed Oil for Fences</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/linseed-oil-for-fences/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/linseed-oil-for-fences/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this article, we will explore a natural alternative to traditional paint for wood siding - linseed oil. Painting a house with toxic chemicals that are not biodegradable is not only harmful to the environment, but it also requires constant maintenance as the paint chips and peels over time. To avoid these issues and provide long-lasting protection to your wood siding, we will discuss how to create a wood pigment protector using linseed oil, turpentine, and earth pigment powder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Finishing All My DIY Outdoor Cedar Furniture Builds with Teak Oil</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/finish-for-cedar-outdoor-furniture/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/finish-for-cedar-outdoor-furniture/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this article, we will discuss the process of finishing outdoor cedar furniture using teak oil. If you&amp;rsquo;re a fan of DIY furniture projects, you may have seen Nathan Builds, a popular YouTube channel. Nathan has made various types of outdoor furniture using cedar two by fours and fence pickets. The use of different sizes of wood creates an appealing contrast, making it an ideal choice for his furniture projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How Durable Is The World&#39;s Strongest Wood? A Comprehensive Waterjet Test</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/pine-janka-scale/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/pine-janka-scale/</guid>
      <description>Introduction
In this article, we will be exploring the strength and durability of different types of wood by subjecting them to a series of tests. The Waterjet Channel on YouTube conducts experiments to determine the hardness, cutability, sanding capabilities, and burn resistance of various woods. By evaluating the performance of these woods, we can gain a better understanding of their unique characteristics and applications in different industries.
The Janka Hardness Test Explained</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Apply Linseed Oil on Wood: Durability Testing and Waterproofing</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/boiled-linseed-oil-cedar-shingles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/boiled-linseed-oil-cedar-shingles/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this article, we will explore the process of applying linseed oil to wood and determine its durability and waterproofing capabilities. Linseed oil is a popular choice for wood finishes due to its ability to enhance the natural beauty of the wood while providing a protective layer. We will go through the step-by-step process of applying linseed oil and discuss the results of durability testing.
Preparing the Wood Before applying linseed oil, it is crucial to prepare the wood surface properly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> How to Paint Over Stained/Varnished Surfaces Without Sanding: A Step-by-Step Guide</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/stain-over-varnish/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/stain-over-varnish/</guid>
      <description>In this article, we will discuss the process of painting over a glossy, stained, or varnished surface without the need for sanding or stripping. We will guide you through the steps and introduce a product that makes this process quick and easy. By following our instructions, you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to transform any glossy surface into a perfectly painted one with ease.
Step 1: Assess the Surface Before you begin the painting process, it&amp;rsquo;s essential to evaluate the surface you wish to paint.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Revealing the Secret Tool in a Combination Square: A Swiss Precision Tool</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/swiss-precision-combination-square/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/swiss-precision-combination-square/</guid>
      <description>In the world of woodworking and carpentry, the combination square is a staple tool that can be found in every craftsman&amp;rsquo;s toolkit. This versatile tool is used for various purposes, such as striking 90-degree and 45-degree lines, verifying angles, and setting the height of a blade on a table saw. However, there is a hidden gem within the combination square that many people are not aware of - a secret tool that can be a game-changer in your woodworking projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Table Saw vs Track Saw vs Circular Saw: Which Should You Buy?</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/difference-track-vs-circular-saw/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/difference-track-vs-circular-saw/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to choosing between a circular saw, track saw, or table saw, it can be a challenging decision to make. Each tool has its own advantages and limitations, and understanding them is crucial in determining which one is the right fit for your needs. In this article, we will discuss the key differences between these three types of saws, and by the end, you will have a better understanding of which one is best suited for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> This SIMPLE wood finish will save you DAYS of shop time! (Shellac): A Comprehensive Guide</title>
      <link>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/is-shellac-waterproof/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obsessedwoodworking.github.io/posts/is-shellac-waterproof/</guid>
      <description>In the world of wood finishing, shellac was once hailed as the best finish for wood. However, modern finish manufacturers have convinced us that shellac is old-fashioned, and many woodworkers have forgotten the benefits of using it. In this article, we will explore why shellac is a great wood finish, how to use it effectively, and when it is the best choice for your projects. By the end of this article, you will understand why shellac can save you days of shop time and why it deserves a place in your woodworking arsenal.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
